<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="Division" identifier="II" order_by="2" level="1">Division II - Planning and Development</unit>
  <unit label="part" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">PART 12 - LICENSING AND REGULATION</unit>
  <unit label="chapter" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="3">CHAPTER 2. - BUSINESSES AND TRADES</unit>
  <unit label="article" identifier="H" order_by="H" level="4">ARTICLE H. - RENTAL DWELLING REGISTRATION AND PROP NOTIFICATION</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="12-2180" order_by="12-2180" level="5">Sec. 12-2180. - COMPLIANCE WITH PROVISIONS.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>12-2180</section_number>
 <catch_line>COMPLIANCE WITH PROVISIONS.</catch_line>
 <order_by>12-2180</order_by>
 <text>
  <section prefix="(a)">	Any person required by this article to register a rental residential dwelling who files a complete application for registration within ten (10) days following notice from the Inspections Department that this Article applies to the dwelling shall be deemed compliant with this article unless and until the application is denied. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(b)">	It shall be unlawful to rent, to receive rental income from, or to offer for rent a dwelling subject to the registration requirements of this Article beginning ten (10) days after service of notice by the Inspections Department that registration is required under this Article unless a complete application for a ยง12-2177 registration has been submitted for the dwelling. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(c)">	Any mortgagee of record, not otherwise defined as an owner, shall be deemed compliant with this article unless and until the other owners of the rental residential dwelling fail to comply with the registration requirement of this Article. A mortgagee of record, not otherwise defined as an owner, shall not be liable for civil penalties or administrative fees in excess of the liability of the other owners. 
(Ord. No. 2008-415B, ยง1, 7-1-08) 
</section>
 </text>
</law>
