<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="Division" identifier="II" order_by="2" level="1">Division II - Planning and Development</unit>
  <unit label="part" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">PART 12 - LICENSING AND REGULATION</unit>
  <unit label="chapter" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="3">CHAPTER 3. - ANIMALS</unit>
  <unit label="article" identifier="D" order_by="D" level="4">ARTICLE D. - STABLES AND HOLDING FACILITIES</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="12-3031" order_by="12-3031" level="5">Sec. 12-3031. - STABLES FOR CATTLE, GOATS, AND HORSES; GENERALLY.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>12-3031</section_number>
 <catch_line>STABLES FOR CATTLE, GOATS, AND HORSES; GENERALLY.</catch_line>
 <order_by>12-3031</order_by>
 <text>
It shall be unlawful for any person to locate or place, erect or maintain on any property within the corporate limits of the City, a stable for housing cattle, non-pygmy goats, or horses unless such stable is located at least two hundred (200) feet from all neighboring residences. Not more than one head of cattle, one non-pygmy goat or one horse may be kept on a lot less than one acre. A pygmy goat is defined as a goat classified as Capra Hircus and weighing no more than eighty-five (85) pounds and standing no higher than twenty-one (21) inches when measured at the withers. For lots dimensioned one acre and no more than five (5) acres in size, a maximum of three (3) head of cattle, or three (3) goats, or three (3) horses per acre may be kept. More than three (3) head of cattle, three (3) goats, or three (3) horses per acre, but not more than ten (10) head of cattle, or ten (10) goats, or ten (10) horses per acre may be kept on lots containing more than five (5) acres. Every part of a lot set aside for the use of cattle, goats or horses shall be completely enclosed. Stables used for housing cattle, goats, or horses shall comply with all local zoning ordinances and shall be constructed and maintained in conformity with the requirements of the Wake County Board of Health. 
(Code 1959 , ยง4-14; Ord. No. 1982-47-TC-173, ยง1, 12-21-82; Ord. No. 2012-108, ยง1, 10-2-12) 
</text>
</law>
