<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="Division" identifier="II" order_by="2" level="1">Division II - Planning and Development</unit>
  <unit label="part" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="2">PART 8 - PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit>
  <unit label="chapter" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="3">CHAPTER 2. - WATER AND SEWER SERVICE</unit>
  <unit label="article" identifier="B" order_by="B" level="4">ARTICLE B. - WATER AND SEWER EXTENSION POLICIES</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="8-2039" order_by="8-2039" level="5">Sec. 8-2039. - FEES FOR THE INSTALLATION OF WATER AND SEWER SERVICES BY CITY FORCES AND CONTRACTORS WORKING FOR THE CITY.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>8-2039</section_number>
 <catch_line>FEES FOR THE INSTALLATION OF WATER AND SEWER SERVICES BY CITY FORCES AND CONTRACTORS WORKING FOR THE CITY.</catch_line>
 <order_by>8-2039</order_by>
 <text>
  
Size and Type of Service	Lump Sum Fee
¾-inch water* .....	$2,449.00
1-inch water* .....	2,693.00
¾-inch split water (new application) .....	490.00
¾-inch split water (existing application) .....	1,009.00
1-inch split water (new application) .....	834.00
1-inch split water (existing application) .....	1,352.00
4-inch sewer service* .....	3,063.00
*  The City does not install taps across divided roadways, or across roadways/streets measuring forty-five (45) feet or longer as measured from back of curb to back or curb. When no curb exists, the measurement shall be marked from the edge of pavement. 
Sewer only Disconnection fee .....	1,237.00
Sewer only Reconnection fee .....	1,237.00
 
These fees apply to services installed by City forces or contractors working for the City. Fees for water services larger than one (1) inch and sewer services larger than four (4) inches may be installed by a private licensed utility contractor. 
Tap fees for owner-occupied residential structures will be financed by the City for a term of five (5) years at eight (8) percent interest at the homeowner's option; provided that, in those cases in which a property owner owns only one (1) property in the City and that property is a residential structure, that property owner may finance those tap fees in accordance with the provision of this section. 
Water and sewer tap fees relating to public extension projects, initiated after June 30, 1996, are subject to a one-year freeze following service availability as determined by the City Manager or his duly authorized representative. This freeze shall apply only to owners of developed properties within the project area upon which a tap was installed as part of the public extension project. During the one-year freeze period, the eligible property owners may connect to the City system(s) and pay those fees which were in effect on the date the City Council directed construction of the project. All other property owners in the project area shall pay the prevailing tap fee(s) in effect on the date service connection is requested. 
(Ord. No. 1991-894, §§1—3, 12-3-91; Ord. No. 1992-81, §1, 11-4-92; Ord. No. 1996-873, §1, 5-7-96; Ord. No. 1997-55, §1, 2-18-97; Ord. No. 1997-164, 8-5-97; Ord. No. 1998-336, §1, 6-2-98; Ord. No. 1999-557, §1, 5-4-99; Ord. No. 2000-83, §1, 7-5-00; Ord. No. 2001-993, §1, 5-1-01; Ord. No. 2002-198, §1, 5-7-02; Ord. No. 2003-438, §1, 5-6-03; Ord. No. 2004-622, §1, 5-4-04; Ord. No. 2004-714, §§1, 2, 9-21-04; Ord. No. 2009-558, §1, 3-17-09, eff. 7-1-09; Ord. No. 2010-720, §1, 4-6-10, eff. 7-1-10; Ord. No. 2011-881, §1, 5-17-11, eff. 7-1-11; Ord. No. 2012-40, §1, 5-1-12, eff. 7-1-12) 
Editor's note: For the inclusion of Ord. No. 1991-894 as §8-2039, see the editor's note to §10-6081. Former §8-2039 is now §8-2075 
</text>
</law>
