<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="division" identifier="I" order_by="1" level="1">Division I - Charter</unit>
  <unit label="article" identifier="II" order_by="2" level="2">ARTICLE II. - LEGISLATION, GOVERNING BODY, GENERAL POWERS</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="2.2" order_by="2.2" level="3">Sec. 2.2 - NUMBER AND ELECTION OF MEMBERS OF CITY COUNCIL.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>I-II-2.2</section_number>
 <catch_line>NUMBER AND ELECTION OF MEMBERS OF CITY COUNCIL.</catch_line>
 <order_by>2.2</order_by>
 <section prefix="text">
  <section prefix="(a)">	The City Council shall consist of eight (8) members, including the Mayor of the City.
</section>
  <section prefix="(b)">
   <section prefix="(1)">	The City Council shall divide the City into five (5) electoral districts and shall cause a map of the districts to be prepared and filed as provided by G.S. 160A-22 and 160A-23; one member of the City Council shall be apportioned to each district so that each member represents the same number of persons as nearly as possible, except for the members apportioned to the City at large; and the qualified voters of each district shall nominate and elect candidates who reside in the district for the seat apportioned to that district. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(2)">	The qualified voters of the City shall nominate and elect two (2) candidates apportioned to the City at large.
</section>
   <section prefix="(3)">	The Mayor of the City of Raleigh shall be elected by all the qualified voters of the City of Raleigh.
</section>
  </section>
  <section prefix="(c)">	The method of election of the City Council of the City of Raleigh shall be the nonpartisan election and runoff election method to be conducted as provided in G.S. 163-293. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(d)">	Each member of the City Council and the Mayor shall be elected for a term of two years and until his successor is elected and qualified. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(e)">	Vacancies in the City Council shall be filled by the Council for the remainder of the unexpired term.
</section>
  <section prefix="(f)">	Vacancies in the office of Mayor shall be filled by the Council from their own number for the remainder of the unexpired term.
; as amended by Ord. No. 1978-837, ยง1, 7-5-78) 
Amendment note: By Ord. No. 1978-837, adopted July 5, 1978, the City Council amended ยง2.2 above by providing for the nonpartisan election and runoff method of election, pursuant to Part 4 of Article 5 of Chapter 10A of the General Statutes, G.S. 160A-101 et seq. 
</section>
 </section>
 <history>(S.L. 1973, Ch. 319, ยง1(b)</history>
</law>
