<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="Division" identifier="II" order_by="2" level="1">Division II - Planning and Development</unit>
  <unit label="part" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="2">PART 8 - PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit>
  <unit label="chapter" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="3">CHAPTER 2. - WATER AND SEWER SERVICE</unit>
  <unit label="article" identifier="B" order_by="B" level="4">ARTICLE B. - WATER AND SEWER EXTENSION POLICIES</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="8-2063" order_by="8-2063" level="5">Sec. 8-2063. - CITY COUNCIL APPROVAL OF OUTSIDE EXTENSIONS.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>8-2063</section_number>
 <catch_line>CITY COUNCIL APPROVAL OF OUTSIDE EXTENSIONS.</catch_line>
 <order_by>8-2063</order_by>
 <text>
  <section prefix="(a)">	Street standards. 
In prescribing such requirements and prerequisites for approval of the application for utility connections, the Council shall, in approving the subdivision or development, determine the width of streets, the adequacy of drainage, and flood control measures and facilities, the type of paving, the size and type of pipes and other equipment, the location of streets, particularly with respect to their coordination with the street plan of the City, and such other matters with respect to the development or subdivision as the Council in its discretion may deem proper. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(b)">	Water and sewer lines required. 
No private water line, lines or system within any greater than two-acre development or subdivision outside the corporate limits shall be approved for connection with the water system of the City, nor will the City accept any dedication of the same nor will the City agree to furnish water service to consumers within any such development or subdivision, unless, at the same time, there is connected with the City sewerage system and dedicated to the City sewer a sewerage system laid and constructed to City standards sufficient to make available adequate sewerage services for each of the lots within such development or subdivision. No private sewer line, lines, or system within any greater than two-acre development or subdivision outside the corporate limits shall be approved for connection with the sewer system of the City, nor will the City accept any dedication of the same, nor will the City agree to furnish sewer service to consumers within any such development or subdivision, unless, at the same time, there is connected with the City water system and dedicated to the City a water system laid and constructed to City standards sufficient to make available adequate water services for each of the lots within such development or subdivision. These restrictions shall also apply to any properties separated by conveyance after April 17, 1984, except if the property is separated from a parcel which on April 17, 1984 is two (2) acres or less in size. On lots greater than two (2) acres that have existing buildings that are having well and septic tank problems, [these] would be able to use one (1) utility without the other if both utilities are not available to the site. 
In such case where both utilities are not available to a particular tract of land and the property owner wishes to connect to the one that is available, the property owner will be allowed to connect to the particular utility that is available. Available for the purpose of this paragraph shall be defined to mean that the utility is located within one thousand (1,000) feet of the nearest point on the property. 
Cross reference: Property owners located outside City limits which connect to one (1) or more City utilities must submit a voluntary petition annexation, Resolution No. 1993-208. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(c)">	Adequate flood control facilities required. 
The City hereby states a policy of not extending water and/or sewer service facilities, or any other facilities under its control, into areas of Wake County outside the City's Chapter 160A, Article 19 planning jurisdiction, except in unusual circumstances, unless and until areas into which such services are extended and the areas within the Chapter 160A, Article 19 planning jurisdiction of the City are adequately protected through the installation of flood control and other such devices, and unless and until adequate facilities are available for the supply of water and the treatment of sewage. 
Cross reference: Floodprone area regulations, Part 10, Ch. 4. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(d)">	Community systems. 
Developments located outside the corporate limits but within the utilities planning area as provided in the comprehensive plan that install or propose to install a community water system, sanitary sewer system, or both must install said systems in accordance with the City design, materials, and construction standards and methods. Such design, materials, and construction standards and methods are subject to the same regulations as if the community water and community sewer system were connected to the system of Raleigh. If the conditions of G.S. 160A-374 are met by the City, full dedication of a community water system, including all wells, pumps, and utility lines, is required. 
(Ord. No. 1985-577-TC-237, §3, 6-4-85; Ord. No. 1986-892, §1, 11-18-86; Ord. No. 1991-768, §1, 4-16-91; Ord. No. 1995-760-TC-122, §14, TC-20C-95, 11-21-95; Ord. No. 2011-868, §1, 5-3-11) 
Cross reference: Resolution No. 1993-208 requires that connections to City utilities for any property outside corporate limits must be accompanied with a petition for annexation. 
</section>
 </text>
</law>
