<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="Division" identifier="II" order_by="2" level="1">Division II - Planning and Development</unit>
  <unit label="part" identifier="11" order_by="11" level="2">PART 11 - TRANSPORTATION</unit>
  <unit label="chapter" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="3">CHAPTER 2. - MOTOR VEHICLES AND TRAFFIC</unit>
  <unit label="article" identifier="A" order_by="A" level="4">ARTICLE A. - GENERAL PROVISIONS</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="11-2001" order_by="11-2001" level="5">Sec. 11-2001. - DEFINITIONS.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>11-2001</section_number>
 <catch_line>DEFINITIONS.</catch_line>
 <order_by>11-2001</order_by>
 <text>
Whenever in this chapter the words hereinafter defined in this section are used they shall, unless the context requires otherwise, be deemed to have the following meanings: 
Authorized emergency vehicle. An authorized emergency vehicle is any vehicle owned by a Federal, state, County, or municipal law enforcement agency and operated by a member thereof, any vehicle owned and operated by a Fire Department or rescue squad, or any ambulance. 
Block. A block is the part of a street lying between the nearest intersecting streets on either side. 
Car sharing. Car sharing is a membership based service available to all qualified drivers in the community who choose to become members. Members must be offered access to a dispersed network of shared vehicles twenty-four (24) hours a day, seven (7) days a week at unattended self service locations. Car usage is provided without restriction at hourly or per mile rates that include fuel, insurance, and maintenance. Any car sharing service using a parking space reserved for car share vehicles must belong to an organization approved by the Raleigh Public Works Director or his designee. 
Crosswalk. A crosswalk is the part of a roadway ordinarily included within the prolongation or connection of the lateral boundary lines of the adjacent sidewalk at the end of a block, or any part of a roadway indicated for pedestrian crossing by official traffic-control devices. 
Driveway. A way leading from a public street to a place on private property suitable to and regularly used for the passage or standing of motor vehicles when passage to such area of private property is not permanently impeded by any wall, building, or other such structure. A driveway shall consist of a curb cut or other such modification and a regularly accessible suitable area of private property. A curb cut alone, without such area of private property or with access to such area of private property permanently obstructed, shall not constitute a driveway. 
Intersection. An intersection is the area embraced within the prolongation of the lateral curb lines or, if none, then the lateral boundary lines of two (2) or more highways which join one another at any angle whether or not one (1) such highway crosses the other. 
Lane. A lane is a section of roadway between marked lines or between a marked line and the edge of a roadway, which section is set aside for a single file of vehicular traffic, except a section reserved for parking. 
Median. A median is that portion of public right-of-way lying between two (2) roadways and used for the separation of vehicular traffic. A median may be paved or unpaved and may or may not have a raised curb. 
Motor vehicle. A motor vehicle is a vehicle which is self-propelled and designed to run upon the highways, and every vehicle which is pulled by a self propelled vehicle. 
Official time standard. The hours designated in time limitations set by this chapter refer to eastern standard time or eastern daylight saving time as may be in current use within the City by the action of the governing body, the North Carolina General Assembly, or the Congress of the United States. 
Official traffic-control device. An official traffic-control device is a sign, signal, marking, or device, including a parking meter, placed by authority of the governing body of the City for the purpose of regulating vehicular and pedestrian traffic, including parking. 
Parking. Park or parking is the standing of a vehicle, whether occupied or not, on a public highway or street, otherwise than temporarily for the purpose of and while actually engaged in receiving or discharging passengers or in obedience to traffic regulations. 
Parking citation. A parking citation is a printed notice issued by authority of the governing body of this City, informing the individual designated that he or she has violated a provision of this chapter. 
Parking meter. A parking meter is a coin-operated mechanical device used in regulating parking. 
Private road or driveway. A private road or driveway is a road or driveway not open to the use of the public as a matter of right for the purpose of vehicular traffic. 
Roadway. A roadway is the part of a street improved, designed, or ordinarily used for vehicular traffic. 
Sidewalk. A sidewalk is the part of a street improved for pedestrian traffic. 
Stop line. A stop line is a line across a roadway or part of a roadway indicating the point behind which vehicles are required to stop in compliance with an official traffic-control device. 
Street or highway. A street or highway is the entire width between property or right-of-way lines of every way or place of whatever nature, when any part thereof is open to the use of the public as a matter of right for the purpose of vehicular traffic. 
Traffic schedule. A traffic schedule is a separate schedule which is incorporated into by reference and made a part of this chapter, and which designates certain streets, parts of streets, street areas, or times to which a provision of this chapter applies. 
Vehicle. A vehicle is a device in, upon, or by which any person or property is or may be transported or drawn upon a highway, excepting devices moved by human power or used exclusively upon fixed rails or tracks; provided, that for the purposes of this chapter bicycles shall be deemed vehicles. 
(Ord. No. 2012-122, ยง1, 11-20-12, eff. 11-27-12) 
</text>
</law>
