<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="Division" identifier="II" order_by="2" level="1">Division II - Planning and Development</unit>
  <unit label="part" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="2">PART 8 - PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit>
  <unit label="chapter" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="3">CHAPTER 2. - WATER AND SEWER SERVICE</unit>
  <unit label="article" identifier="B" order_by="B" level="4">ARTICLE B. - WATER AND SEWER EXTENSION POLICIES</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="8-2061" order_by="8-2061" level="5">Sec. 8-2061. - APPLICATION.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>8-2061</section_number>
 <catch_line>APPLICATION.</catch_line>
 <order_by>8-2061</order_by>
 <text>
Any person owning or proposing to construct any private utility line or system inside or outside the corporate limits of the City which it is desired to have connected with the public utility lines and systems of the City shall make written application for permission to make such connections, upon forms furnished by the Director of Public Utilities. Applications will be received and acted upon in accordance with the provisions of this article. The application must contain a preliminary utility plan which shall be prepared by a professional engineer registered to practice in the State of North Carolina. The application must also be accompanied by a map made by a professional engineer or registered land surveyor authorized to practice in the State, which map shall show accurately the property to be served with water and/or sewer service, and, if within any real estate development or subdivision, the map shall show the property lines and subdivision of lots and the layout of streets therein. When the private utility lines or systems are to be laid and constructed within any subdivision, such subdivision and the map thereof showing the property lines and subdivision of lots and the layout of streets must have been duly approved in accordance with Chapter 3, Part 10 of this Code before the approval of any application for permission to make connections with the utility system of the City. Fees of two hundred dollars ($200.00) for main extensions and three hundred dollars ($300.00) for pump stations permits will be paid by the developer at the time engineering plans are submitted for review. 
(Ord. No. 1985-543, ยง25, 4-16-85; Ord. No. 1986-778, ยง1, 5-6-86; Ord. No. 1991-781, ยง1, 5-21-91; Ord. No. 2002-196, ยง1, 5-7-02) 
State law reference: Utility construction plans and specifications, G.S. 89C-19. 
</text>
</law>
