<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="Division" identifier="II" order_by="2" level="1">Division II - Planning and Development</unit>
  <unit label="part" identifier="11" order_by="11" level="2">PART 11 - TRANSPORTATION</unit>
  <unit label="chapter" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="3">CHAPTER 2. - MOTOR VEHICLES AND TRAFFIC</unit>
  <unit label="article" identifier="J" order_by="J" level="4">ARTICLE J. - PARKING AND STANDING</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="11-2182" order_by="11-2182" level="5">Sec. 11-2182. - CONTROLLED PARKING RESIDENTIAL AREA.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>11-2182</section_number>
 <catch_line>CONTROLLED PARKING RESIDENTIAL AREA.</catch_line>
 <order_by>11-2182</order_by>
 <text>
  <section prefix="(a)">
   <section prefix="(1)">	The area either contains at least eight (8) contiguous block faces abutted by property primarily in residential zoning districts or is a contiguous expansion of an existing controlled parking residential area and the area is abutted by property primarily in residential zoning districts. A block face as used herein shall mean one side of a street between two (2) intersecting streets; 
</section>
   <section prefix="(2)">	A petition identifying the boundaries of and streets within the proposed controlled parking residential area has been presented to the Department of Transportation requesting such designation and signed by adult residents from at least seventy (70) per cent of the living units contained in each block of the proposed controlled parking residential area; 
</section>
   <section prefix="(3)">	A parking study, of one (1) observation each two (2) hours, and conducted between the hours of 8:00 a.m. and 4:00 p.m. on a week day reveals that at least an average of seventy (70) per cent of the parking capacity of the proposed controlled parking residential area is occupied; and, 
</section>
   <section prefix="(4)">	A minimum of thirty-three (33) per cent of the parked vehicles are registered to addresses outside the proposed controlled parking residential area. 
</section>
  </section>
  <section prefix="(b)">
   <section prefix="(1)">	Controlled parking residential area shall mean an area designated herein for restricted residential parking pursuant to criteria established in subsection (a) hereof. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(2)">	Residential parking permit decal shall mean a special permit issued hereunder by the Revenue Collector and authorizing the vehicle bearing such permit to be parked for a period in excess of two (2) hours in a controlled parking residential area. 
</section>
  </section>
  <section prefix="(c)">	Permit decal display. 
The residential parking permit decal shall be attached to the left rear bumper of the vehicle for which issued and shall contain the vehicle license number, year of issue, and the identification number of the controlled parking residential area for which issued. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(d)">	Eligibility for permit decal. 
A resident of a controlled parking residential area is eligible to receive one (1) residential parking permit decal for each vehicle which is principally operated by the resident. The Revenue Collector shall verify the residence address of persons obtaining such decals and shall record on the face of the decal the license number of the vehicle and the letter designation of the controlled parking residential area for which issued. As proof of residency, the Revenue Collector may require utility bills, notarized affidavits of the landlord, auto registration cards and other documentation deemed necessary naming the permittee and showing an address within the controlled parking area. Residential parking permit decals issued for vehicles used by nonresidents of the controlled parking residential area or used for purposes of daily commuting to the area or for purposes of storage of nonresidential vehicles are void. 
Any health care provider who provides regular medical or health services for more than two (2) continuous hours to persons residing in a controlled parking residential area may also apply to the Revenue Collector. Such persons may receive a residential parking permit decal or a removable windshield placard. When the permit or placard is properly displayed, all parking rights and privileges pursuant to subsection (g) extended to vehicles displaying a residential parking permit decal shall apply. The Revenue Collector shall verify the delivery of medical and health services of persons requesting a decal or placard. As proof, the Revenue Collector may require a medical doctor's certification that regular care is needed for persons residing in a controlled parking residential area. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(e)">	Permit issuance fee. 
The Revenue Collector shall issue residential parking permit decals for an administrative charge of ten dollars ($10.00) per decal per year. The charge shall not be prorated for partial years. No residential parking permit decal shall be transferred to another vehicle. The charge for duplicate permit decals shall be ten dollars ($10.00) except that a replacement decal shall be issued without cost if an individual returns a current used decal and shows proof of purchase to the Revenue Collector or if an individual shows proof to the Revenue Collector of change in registration number for the vehicle. Residential parking permit decals shall be issued on a calendar year basis, and shall expire at midnight on December 31 of each year. Provided it shall not be unlawful to continue to park an authorized vehicle in a controlled parking residential area during the period between December 31 and February 14 inclusive, if a residential parking permit decal for the vehicle was issued for the previous immediate calendar year. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(f)">
   <section prefix="(1)">	No person shall display a residential parking permit decal on a vehicle unless such vehicle displays the same vehicle license number as shown on the residential parking permit decal; and any such use or display except as authorized herein shall constitute a violation of this Code by the permittee and by the person who so used or displayed the residential parking permit decal. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(2)">	It shall constitute a violation of this Code for any person to falsely represent himself as eligible for a residential parking permit decal or to furnish any false information in an application to the Revenue Collector in order to obtain a residential parking permit decal. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(3)">	The Revenue Collector is authorized to revoke the residential parking permit of any permittee found to be in violation of this section, and, upon written notification thereof, the permittee shall surrender such permit to the Revenue Collector. Failure, when so requested, to surrender a residential parking permit, so revoked, shall constitute a violation of this Code. 
</section>
  </section>
  <section prefix="(g)">	Compliance with signs. 
When signs are erected adjacent to streets in the controlled parking residential areas listed in this section, no person shall park a vehicle for longer than two (2) hours between the hours of 8:00 a.m. and 5:00 p.m., Monday through Friday, unless such vehicle has a properly displayed residential parking permit decal for the area in which parked provided that these provisions shall not apply to locations specified in §11-2172 (no parking zones), §11-2171 (places no-parking), §11-2173 (no stopping or standing) §11-2174 (time limited parking), §11-2177 (loading zones), §11-2178 (bus zones), §11-2202 (meter zones). A residential parking permit shall not guarantee or reserve to the holder a parking space within a designated controlled parking residential area. 
(Ord. No. 1979-8, 2-6-79; Ord. No. 1981-657A, §1, 5-5-81; Ord. No. 1982-834, §1, 2-2-82; Ord. No. 1996-820, §1, 2-6-96; Ord. No. 2007-182, §1, 3-20-07) 
Editor's note: It should be noted that, with the adoption of Ord. No. 1981-735, on Sept. 1, 1981, §11-2182 was amended &quot;to reflect the addition of the following entry in Residential Area A, Controlled Parking: 
Chamberlain Street, both sides, Hillsborough Street to Stafford Street.&quot;
Annotation: The U.S. Supreme Court, in County Board of Arlington County, Virginia v. Richards, 54 L.Ed. 2d 4 (1977) upheld the constitutional validity of controlled parking in residential areas. 
</section>
 </text>
</law>
