<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="Division" identifier="II" order_by="2" level="1">Division II - Planning and Development</unit>
  <unit label="part" identifier="11" order_by="11" level="2">PART 11 - TRANSPORTATION</unit>
  <unit label="chapter" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="3">CHAPTER 2. - MOTOR VEHICLES AND TRAFFIC</unit>
  <unit label="article" identifier="J" order_by="J" level="4">ARTICLE J. - PARKING AND STANDING</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="11-2175" order_by="11-2175" level="5">Sec. 11-2175. - PARKING LIMITATIONS ON CITY-OWNED FACILITIES.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>11-2175</section_number>
 <catch_line>PARKING LIMITATIONS ON CITY-OWNED FACILITIES.</catch_line>
 <order_by>11-2175</order_by>
 <text>
  <section prefix="(a)">	Parking of vehicles on the lot owned by the City and located along the west side of McDowell Street and along the north side of Hargett Street shall be limited to vehicles owned by the City, vehicles operated by members of the City Council, and vehicles operated by City employees and used by them officially and regularly in connection with the performance of their duties in their employment by the City. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(b)">	Except as expressly provided and permitted by this paragraph, in order to make available adequate parking facilities for the vehicles being used by City employees and officials in the prosecution of the City's business, it shall be unlawful for any person to stop, stand or park any vehicle on such lot and it shall be unlawful for the owner of any vehicle to suffer or permit any vehicle owned by him to be parked on such lot. The City Manager is authorized and directed to cause the parking spaces within such lot to be appropriately designated and to assign specific spaces for the exclusive use of specific officials or employees or of specific department or divisions, and not more than eight (8) spaces for the use of members of the City Council; and when so designated and properly marked by appropriate signs, it shall be unlawful for any person to park within any space not designated and authorized for his use in accordance with this paragraph. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(c)">	If at any time the City Manager shall determine that the parking space is not needed for the parking of City vehicles and vehicles being used on official City business the City Manager is authorized to properly designate and make the parking space available for general public use or for reserved public parking. Such spaces may be designated by parking meters, signs, striping or any other method selected by the City Manager. Any vehicle parked in violation of the rules establishing such public or reserved spaces shall be an offense and the violation may be enforced by any lawful method, including towing, by which any other violation of City parking regulations may be enforced. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(d)">	The City Manager is authorized and directed to cause driveways to be designated and marked on the lot for the purpose of ingress and egress to and from the parking spaces, and when so designated, it shall be unlawful for any person to park any vehicle within any driveway or to permit, or to allow any vehicle owned by him to be parked therein. It shall be unlawful for any person to park at any time or at any place within the lot so as to block the passage to or from any parking space or to prevent the use of any parking spaces by the person for whom the parking space has been designated in accordance with the provisions of this paragraph. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(e)">	The City Manager is authorized and directed, in his discretion, to cause parking spaces, traffic lanes, including one-way lanes, and loading zones, to be designated and marked on the municipal auditorium parking lot and on the service drive adjacent to the Sheraton Capital Center Hotel and connecting Cabarrus Street with Salisbury Street. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(f)">	The City Manager is authorized and directed in his discretion, to cause parking spaces, time limit parking spaces, metered parking spaces, loading zones, no parking zones, handicap spaces and traffic lanes, including one-way lanes to be designated and marked on all City properties. 
Such spaces shall be subject to the same enforcement provisions and practices afforded such spaces on public streets. The City Manager shall have authority to establish time limits and parking meter rates identified in §§11-2174, 11-2205 and 11-2206. In addition, he shall be authorized to increase rates and vary time limits as he deems appropriate for such spaces. 
(Code 1959 , §21-34(b)—(d); Ord. No. 1982-876, §1, 3-23-82; Ord. No. 1993-151, §1, 4-6-93; Ord. No. 1998-454, §17, 11-4-98; Ord. No. 2008-434, §§1, 2, 8-5-08) 
Cross reference: Parking areas in parks, §§9-2013, 9-2014 
</section>
 </text>
</law>
