<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="Division" identifier="II" order_by="2" level="1">Division II - Planning and Development</unit>
  <unit label="part" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">PART 7 - SOLID WASTE SERVICES [1]</unit>
  <unit label="chapter" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="3">CHAPTER 2. - SOLID WASTE COLLECTION [2]</unit>
  <unit label="article" identifier="A" order_by="A" level="4">ARTICLE A. - GENERAL PROVISIONS</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="7-2001" order_by="7-2001" level="5">Sec. 7-2001. - DEFINITIONS.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>7-2001</section_number>
 <catch_line>DEFINITIONS.</catch_line>
 <order_by>7-2001</order_by>
 <text>
  <section prefix="(a)">	Waste. 
Useless, unused, unwanted, or discarded materials resulting from natural community activities, including solids, liquids, and gases. Clean excavated earth devoid of any of the substances described in parts (1) through (9) of this section shall not be considered waste material for the purpose of §7-2007 of this Chapter and will therefore be exempt from the tipping fee. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(b)">	Refuse. 
Solid waste, including but not limited to garbage, rubbish and ashes. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(c)">	Garbage. 
Animal and vegetable refuse resulting from the handling, preparation, cooking, and consumption of food, including a minimum amount of liquid necessary incident thereto. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(d)">	Ashes. 
Refuse resulting from the burning of wood, coal, coke, and other combustible material. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(e)">	Rubbish. 
Refuse (exclusive of garbage and ashes) including but not limited to paper, rags, cartons, boxes, wood, excelsior, tires, rubber, leather, tin cans, metals, mineral matter, glass, crockery and dust, except for dust incidental to excavated earth. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(f)">	Building rubbish. 
Rubbish from construction, remodeling, and repair operations on houses, commercial buildings, and other structures, including but not limited to stones, brick, plaster, lumber, concrete, and waste parts occasioned by installations and replacements. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(g)">	Combustible refuse. 
Refuse, capable of incineration or burning, such as garbage, paper, rags, boxes and wood. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(h)">	Noncombustible refuse. 
Refuse not capable of incineration or burning, such as ashes, tin cans, metals, mineral matter, crockery, and glass. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(i)">	Industrial waste. 
Waste from factories, processing plants, and other manufacturing enterprises. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(j)">	Regulations. 
Regulations of the City Manager of the City, now or hereafter in effect, promulgated under this chapter or other authority. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(k)">	White goods. 
Residential appliances limited to washing machines, clothes dryers, stoves, ranges, ovens, refrigerators, freezers, dishwashers, and water heaters. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(l)">	Sharps. 
Needles, syringes with attached needles, capillary tubes, slides and cover slips. 
(Code 1959 , §19-22; Ord. No. 1983-98, §1, 4-19-83; Ord. No. 1985-639A, §§1—5, 9-17-85; Ord. No. 1995-760-TC-122, §12, TC-20C-95, 11-21-95; Ord. No. 1998-361, §§1—6, 6-11-98; Ord. No. 1998-454, §9, 11-4-98)  
</section>
 </text>
</law>
