<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="division" identifier="I" order_by="1" level="1">Division I - Charter</unit>
  <unit label="article" identifier="VI" order_by="6" level="2">ARTICLE VI. - MUNICIPAL FUNCTIONS</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="6.5" order_by="6.5" level="3">Sec. 6.5 - CERTIFICATE OF CITY ACCOUNTANT PREREQUISITE TO EXPENDITURE OF PUBLIC FUNDS.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>I-VI-6.5</section_number>
 <catch_line>CERTIFICATE OF CITY ACCOUNTANT PREREQUISITE TO EXPENDITURE OF PUBLIC FUNDS.</catch_line>
 <order_by>6.5</order_by>
 <section prefix="text">
  <section prefix="(a)">	No contract or agreement requiring the payment of money, or requisition for supplies or materials, shall be made, and no warrant or order for the payment of money shall be drawn upon the treasury of the City unless provision for the payment thereof has been made by (a) an appropriation ordinance or resolution as required by law, or (b) through the means of bonds or notes duly authorized by the General Assembly and by the City Council, and further authorized, in all cases required by law or by the constitution, by a vote of qualified voters or taxpayers, or otherwise; nor shall such contract, agreement or requisition be made unless the unencumbered balance of such appropriation or provision remains sufficient for such payment. No contract or agreement or requisition requiring the payment of money shall be valid unless the same be in writing, and unless the same shall have printed, written or typewritten thereon a statement signed by the City Accountant as follows: &quot;Provision for the payment of the moneys to fall due under this agreement has been made by appropriation duly made, or by bonds or notes duly authorized, as required by the Local Government Act.&quot; 
</section>
  <section prefix="(b)">	Before making such certificate, the City Accountant shall ascertain that a sufficient unencumbered balance of the specific appropriation remains for the payment of the obligation, or that bonds or notes have been so authorized proceeds of which are applicable to such payment, and the appropriation or provision so made shall thereafter be deemed unencumbered by the amount to be paid on such contract or agreement until the City is discharged therefrom. No claim against the City shall be paid except by means of a warrant or order on the City Treasurer signed by the head of the department for which the expense was incurred, nor unless the bill or claim for which the warrant or order is given shall have been presented to and approved by the City Accountant, or in case of his disapproval of such claim or bill, by the City Council. The City Council shall not approve any claim or bill which has been disallowed by the City Accountant without entering upon the minutes of the City Council its reason for approving the same in such detail as may show the City Council's reason for reversing the City Accountant's disallowance. No warrant or order, except a warrant or order for payment of maturing bonds, notes or interest coupons thereto appertaining, and except a warrant or order for the payment of any bill or claim approved by the City Council over the disallowance of the City Accountant, as above provided, shall be valid unless the same shall bear the signature of the City Accountant below a statement which he shall cause to be written, printed or typewritten thereon containing the words: &quot;Provision for the payment of this warrant (or order) has been made by an appropriation duly made or a bond or note duly authorized, as required by the Local Government Act.&quot; 
</section>
 </section>
</law>
