<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="Division" identifier="II" order_by="2" level="1">Division II - Planning and Development</unit>
  <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">PART 4 - COMMUNITY SERVICES [1]</unit>
  <unit label="chapter" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="3">CHAPTER 1. - THE DEPARTMENT OF COMMUNITY SERVICES</unit>
  <unit label="article" identifier="A" order_by="A" level="4">ARTICLE A. - GENERAL PROVISIONS</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="4-1003" order_by="4-1003" level="5">Sec. 4-1003. - FUNCTIONS AND DUTIES OF THE DEPARTMENT.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>4-1003</section_number>
 <catch_line>FUNCTIONS AND DUTIES OF THE DEPARTMENT.</catch_line>
 <order_by>4-1003</order_by>
 <text>
  <section prefix="(a)">	Documenting the needs of the citizens of Raleigh in terms of human services.
</section>
  <section prefix="(b)">	Documenting the services and opportunities that are presently available.
</section>
  <section prefix="(c)">	Determining what additional services and opportunities are needed and to propose appropriate and feasible new programs for meeting these needs. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(d)">	Identifying those individuals within the community who are most likely going to benefit from the services and opportunities that are needed. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(e)">	Providing a means for making all persons aware of the services and opportunities that are available. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(f)">	Identifying and recommending responsible agents, including the State, County, private agencies, the City Community Services Department, and others to implement and coordinate the programs for the provision of services. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(g)">	Administering human service programs as designated by Council including the delivery and evaluation of services based on assessed needs and provisions for citizen participation in planning and delivery of services. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(h)">	Performing other functions and duties as prescribed by the City Manager.
Charter reference: Authority to engage in socio-economic programs, ยง2.14(70). 
State law reference: Human relations programs, community action and manpower development, G.S. 160A-492. 
</section>
 </text>
</law>
