<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="Division" identifier="II" order_by="2" level="1">Division II - Planning and Development</unit>
  <unit label="part" identifier="11" order_by="11" level="2">PART 11 - TRANSPORTATION</unit>
  <unit label="chapter" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="3">CHAPTER 2. - MOTOR VEHICLES AND TRAFFIC</unit>
  <unit label="article" identifier="J" order_by="J" level="4">ARTICLE J. - PARKING AND STANDING</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="11-2188" order_by="11-2188" level="5">Sec. 11-2188. - EXTRAORDINANRY IMPACT EVENTS.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>11-2188</section_number>
 <catch_line>EXTRAORDINANRY IMPACT EVENTS.</catch_line>
 <order_by>11-2188</order_by>
 <text>
The City Manager shall have the authority to suspend parking regulations and to reserve on street parking spaces in certain situations. Any individual or business may apply to the City Manager for a reserved spot on one of the City streets set out below. The application shall be submitted at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance of the time desired for the reservation. The fee for a reserved space on the street is one hundred dollars ($100.00) if the vehicle has up to four (4) wheels and two hundred dollars ($200.00) if the vehicle has more than four (4) wheels or is in any other way an oversize vehicle. It is the sole discretion of the City Manager as to what vehicles are appropriate for on street parking and his decision is final. Before granting such a permit the City Manager shall find that the event is of such a spontaneous nature and parking impact that special parking should be provided to facilitate public safety and optimum traffic flow. No permit granted under this ordinance shall extend more than five (5) calendar days. At the expiration of the five (5) day period the applicant may reapply or seek a longer waiver from the City Council. The authority granted herein shall extend only within an area bounded by Edenton Street on the North, Dawson Street on the West, South Street on the South, and Wilmington Street on the East. Nothing herein shall allow parking on sidewalks. 
(Ord. No. 2007-240, ยง1, 6-5-07) 
</text>
</law>
