<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="Division" identifier="II" order_by="2" level="1">Division II - Planning and Development</unit>
  <unit label="part" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">PART 12 - LICENSING AND REGULATION</unit>
  <unit label="chapter" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="3">CHAPTER 2. - BUSINESSES AND TRADES</unit>
  <unit label="article" identifier="B" order_by="B" level="4">ARTICLE B. - VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="12-2030" order_by="12-2030" level="5">Sec. 12-2030. - IDENTIFICATION OF VEHICLES.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>12-2030</section_number>
 <catch_line>IDENTIFICATION OF VEHICLES.</catch_line>
 <order_by>12-2030</order_by>
 <text>
  <section prefix="(a)">	Subject to the approval of the taxicab inspector, each owner of a taxicab business shall adopt a color scheme for painting his cabs distinct from that of any other owner, and may adopt an identifying design, monogram or other insignia. All taxicabs of each owner shall be the same color scheme. The owner of a cab may adopt the color scheme of another cab owner, if (1) both owners' cabs are operating under the same business name and (2) both owners agree to the adoption of the color scheme, and that the owners must present a written agreement to the Police Chief or his designee specifying who owns the company name and colors, that permission is being given to use the name and colors, and that the permission to use the name and colors may be revoked upon written notice to the borrowing owner and the Police Chief or his designee. A name identifying the owner (i.e., taxicab company), taxicab number, and telephone number(s) shall be painted with permanent paint on both sides and rear of each cab with letters and numbers at least four (4) inches high or greater on sides, and with a cab number at rear of at least four (4) inches high at a location to be designated by the taxicab inspector. If a taxicab is used for providing both premium taxi service and shared taxi service, separate telephone numbers for the two (2) services shall be painted on it, and the telephone number associated with the shared taxi service shall be identified by the label &quot;shared taxi.&quot; 
</section>
  <section prefix="(b)">	Colors of paint to be used for lettering and number shall be of sharp contrast with color of surface paint to which this is applied, so as to be evenly visible at a reasonable distance, especially at nighttime with streetlights. No lettering or numbers shall be acceptable which have been painted upon a sheet of metal or other material which in turn can be removed or detached to conceal the identification of such cab company and cab number, provided that an owner who operates under the name of another owner may use the same color scheme as such other owner. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(c)">	No vehicle covered by the terms of this chapter shall be licensed nor shall a permit be issued for any vehicle whose color scheme, identifying design, monogram or insignia to be used thereon shall conflict with or imitate any color scheme, identifying design, monogram or insignia used on a vehicle or vehicles already operating under a permit issued pursuant to this article, in such a manner as to be misleading or tending to deceive the public; provided, after a license or permit has been issued for a taxicab hereunder, if the color scheme, identifying design, monogram or insignia thereof is changed so as to be in conflict with or imitate any existing approved color scheme, identifying design, monogram or insignia used by any other owner in such a manner as to be misleading or tending to deceive the public, the license of or permit covering such taxicab or taxicabs shall be suspended or revoked. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(d)">	It is a violation of this article for any owner to engage in false or misleading marketing or advertising included but not limited to the use of the name or color scheme of a competing taxi company licensed under the provisions of this article. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(e)">	In lieu of paint, any material required by this section to be painted on a taxicab may be placed on the cab through the use of an adhesive decal containing the required information and name. This authorization does not include or permit the use of magnetic signs or devices to convey the required information. 
(Code 1959 , §22-10; Ord. No. 1980-487, §12, 10-7-80; Ord. No. 1988-220, §1, 7-19-88; Ord. No. 1999-691, §§4, 5, 11-16-99; Ord. No. 2003-390, §2, 2-18-03) 
</section>
 </text>
</law>
