<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="Division" identifier="II" order_by="2" level="1">Division II - Planning and Development</unit>
  <unit label="part" identifier="9" order_by="9" level="2">PART 9 - PARKS, RECREATION AND CULTURAL AFFAIRS</unit>
  <unit label="chapter" identifier="10" order_by="10" level="3">CHAPTER 10. - ARTS COMMISSION [8]</unit>
  <unit label="article" identifier="B" order_by="B" level="4">ARTICLE B. - PUBLIC ART</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="9-10006" order_by="9-10006" level="5">Sec. 9-10006. - PUBLIC ART AND DESIGN BOARD.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>9-10006</section_number>
 <catch_line>PUBLIC ART AND DESIGN BOARD.</catch_line>
 <order_by>9-10006</order_by>
 <text>
The Chair of the Arts Commission shall, within thirty days of the enactment of this ordinance, appoint a Public Art and Design Board. The membership of the Board shall be seven (7) members. The members of the Board may be residents or nonresidents of the City and shall be appointed by the Arts Commission Chair. Subsequent members shall be appointed by the Chair of the Arts Commission and serve according to the time and term limits of Part One, Chapter 4 of the Raleigh City Code. The Public Art and Design Board shall develop a public art policy establishing guidelines for the Public Art Program and will forward the same to the City Council for approval. The City Manager shall review all eligible projects approved as a part of the annual Capital Improvement Program (CIP) and refer them to the Public Art and Design Board. The Public Art and Design Board may request the City Manager to review his recommendation if it feels that an eligible project was not forwarded for review. The Public Art and Design Board shall collect all available information about the project including budget, site, schedule and constituent interests. The Public Art and Design Board shall then determine the desirability of a call for artists and the nature and geographical extent of that call. Once the Public Art and Design Board has determined a project is appropriate for public art it shall appoint an Artist Selection Panel (ASP) ranging in size from three (3) to seven (7) members to serve in selecting art for the project. Before the appointment of the first ASP the Arts Commission shall establish written criteria to use in selecting art for public placement. At least one member of the ASP must be a member of the Public Art and Design Board. The other members may be an artist, an arts professional, a design professional, and a representative of the department or agency in whose building or on whose property the proposed work will be located. The members are not required to be members of the Arts Commission. The department or agency representative will be named by the City Manager. The ASP shall interview and select an artist for the project and forward that recommendation to the Public Art and Design Board which will approve or disapprove the recommendation. If the recommendation is approved it will be forwarded to the City Council as information. The City Manager will then negotiate a contract between the City and the artist. 
(Ord. No. 2009-563, ยง2, 3-17-09, eff. 7-1-09; Ord. No. 2009-643, ยง1, 9-1-09; Ord. No. 2011-952, ยง1, 10-4-11) 
</text>
</law>
