<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="Division" identifier="II" order_by="2" level="1">Division II - Planning and Development</unit>
  <unit label="part" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">PART 12 - LICENSING AND REGULATION</unit>
  <unit label="chapter" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="3">CHAPTER 2. - BUSINESSES AND TRADES</unit>
  <unit label="article" identifier="E" order_by="E" level="4">ARTICLE E. - MASSAGES [6]</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="12-2134" order_by="12-2134" level="5">Sec. 12-2134. - LICENSING OF MASSAGE BUSINESS OPERATORS.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>12-2134</section_number>
 <catch_line>LICENSING OF MASSAGE BUSINESS OPERATORS.</catch_line>
 <order_by>12-2134</order_by>
 <text>
  <section prefix="(a)">	No person, partnership, corporation, or association shall operate a massage business as herein defined unless such person, partnership, corporation, or association shall have first applied for and received the regulatory license provided by this section. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(b)">
   <section prefix="(1)">	If the applicant is a person, the name and residence address of such person. If the applicant is a partnership, corporation or association, the name, residence address, and social security number of all persons having any legal or beneficial interest in such applicant; 
</section>
   <section prefix="(2)">	The address of the premises where the massage business shall be located. Nothing in this subsection shall prevent a massagist employed by a licensed massage business from performing massages on behalf of that business at locations removed from the physical premises where the massage business is licensed; 
</section>
   <section prefix="(3)">	A complete statement of all convictions of any person(s) whose name(s) is (are) required to be given in paragraph (b)(1) above, for any felony, for any offense involving the sale of narcotics or controlled substances, or for prostitution or any violation of any law relative to prostitution; 
</section>
   <section prefix="(4)">	A complete statement of any revocation, by any governmental unit, of any license to operate a massage business or to engage in the business or profession of massage held by any person(s) whose name(s) is (are) required to be given in paragraph (b)(1) above; 
</section>
   <section prefix="(5)">	A complete statement of any conviction of any person(s) whose name(s) is (are) required to be given in paragraph (b)(1) above, for violation of any statute, law, ordinance, or regulation of any government concerning the operation of a massage business or the business or profession of massage; 
</section>
   <section prefix="(6)">	The name and address of any massage business or other establishment owned or operated by any person(s) whose name(s) is (are) required to be given in paragraph (b)(1) or profession of massage is carried on; 
</section>
   <section prefix="(7)">	A description of any other business to be operated on the same premises or on adjoining premises owned or controlled by the applicant; 
</section>
   <section prefix="(8)">	A list of the names, addresses, North Carolina massage and bodywork therapy license numbers, and home telephone numbers, of all employees of the establishment. The list shall indicate which employees will perform massage. 
</section>
  </section>
  <section prefix="(c)">	The Revenue Collector shall transmit a copy of the application to the Police Department for an investigative report; to the inspections division to determine compliance with all zoning and building regulations and ordinances; and to the Fire Department to determine compliance with any law relating to fire protection. The Police and Fire Departments and the inspections division shall, within a reasonable time, not to exceed thirty (30) days, report the results of their examinations to the Revenue Collector. An applicant who, consistent with zoning regulations, lawfully operates the massage business out of the applicant's home and who signs a statement under oath that the applicant will not perform massage within the home or allow the public to enter the home in connection with the massage business is not required to submit to a building or fire prevention inspection. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(d)">
   <section prefix="(1)">	The application contains no misstatement of fact;
</section>
   <section prefix="(2)">	All persons employed as massagists or who will perform massage hold a valid license to practice massage and bodywork therapy issued by the State of North Carolina. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(3)">	The massage business operator agrees to supervise adequately the activities of the massagists who work in the massage business. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(4)">	The applicant, or any person having any legal or beneficial ownership interest in the applicant, has not been convicted of any crime involving sexual misconduct, including but not limited to a violation of: G.S. 14-177—14-202.4 (offenses against public morality and decency); G.S. 14-203—14-208 (prostitution); §§13-3002 and 13-2015 of this Code; any Federal statute relating to prostitution; any crime involving the sale of narcotics or controlled substances, or any law or ordinance of any governmental unit concerning or related to the business or profession of massage; 
</section>
   <section prefix="(5)">	The applicant conforms to all requirements of applicable zoning, building, and fire prevention codes, unless the applicant is exempt from building and fire prevention inspections as set out above. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(6)">	The applicant or any person having a legal or beneficial ownership interest in the applicant has not, for the three-year period preceding the application, had a previously issued license for engaging in the business or profession of massage revoked; and 
</section>
   <section prefix="(7)">	The business, by reason of the manner or place in which it is to be conducted, will not constitute a nuisance or in any other manner amount to a menace to good order, the public health, safety or morals. 
</section>
  </section>
  <section prefix="(e)">	Upon approval of the application and upon receipt of a fifty-dollar license fee, the collector of revenue shall issue a regulatory license to applicant. 
(Ord. No. 2001-935, §3, 2-6-01) 
</section>
 </text>
</law>
