<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="Division" identifier="II" order_by="2" level="1">Division II - Planning and Development</unit>
  <unit label="part" identifier="11" order_by="11" level="2">PART 11 - TRANSPORTATION</unit>
  <unit label="chapter" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="3">CHAPTER 2. - MOTOR VEHICLES AND TRAFFIC</unit>
  <unit label="article" identifier="L" order_by="L" level="4">ARTICLE L. - SIGNING AND TRAFFIC ROUTING IN THE EVENT OF STREET OBSTRUCTION</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="11-2231" order_by="11-2231" level="5">Sec. 11-2231. - DEFINITIONS.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>11-2231</section_number>
 <catch_line>DEFINITIONS.</catch_line>
 <order_by>11-2231</order_by>
 <text>
The following words as used in the provisions of this article shall have the following meanings: 
Street shall mean any paved portion, including curbing and gutters, located on any right-of-way conveyed to, dedicated to, or purchased by the State of North Carolina or the City, and which paved portion is used by the public for the passage of motor vehicle, vehicle, and pedestrian traffic. &quot;Street&quot; as herein defined shall not include any portion of a sidewalk. 
Obstruction shall mean any object, hole, excavation, spoil from an excavation, stored building material, or other condition which renders any portion of a street impassable to motor vehicle, vehicle or pedestrian traffic; or, which creates the threat of imminent danger to the health, safety or property of any person using the street for the purpose of motor vehicle, vehicle or pedestrian traffic; or, which creates the threat of imminent danger to the health, safety or property of any person using the street for the purpose of motor vehicle, vehicle or pedestrian traffic passage; provided that traffic cones or other devices used to protect wet pavement marking shall not be considered as obstructions. 
Manual shall mean the &quot;Traffic Control Manual for Construction and Maintenance, City of Raleigh.&quot; This manual shall be kept on file at all times in the office of the City Clerk. 
Emergency situation. An &quot;emergency situation&quot; exists when the obstruction results from or is caused by any unanticipated event or happening which endangers the health or safety of persons using or desiring to use the obstructed street. Such emergency situation continues for the reasonable length of time necessary for the person, persons, firm or corporation working to remove the obstruction to comply with the requirements of this article in a manner consistent with providing protection for the health, safety and property of persons using or desiring to use the obstructed street. 
(Code 1959 , ยง19-33) 
Cross reference: Street responsibilities of the Department of Public Works, Part 7, Chs. 1, 2. 
</text>
</law>
