<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="Division" identifier="II" order_by="2" level="1">Division II - Planning and Development</unit>
  <unit label="part" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">PART 12 - LICENSING AND REGULATION</unit>
  <unit label="chapter" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="3">CHAPTER 1. - STREETS AND PUBLIC WAYS</unit>
  <unit label="article" identifier="B" order_by="B" level="4">ARTICLE B. - STREET USE AND CLEANLINESS</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="12-1024" order_by="12-1024" level="5">Sec. 12-1024. - PEDDLERS' TIME ON STREET LIMITED; PRESENCE RESTRICTED IN CERTAIN AREA; IMPEDING PEDESTRIANS PROHIBITED; WASTE RECEPTACLE REQUIRED ON STAND, CART, ETC.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>12-1024</section_number>
 <catch_line>PEDDLERS' TIME ON STREET LIMITED; PRESENCE RESTRICTED IN CERTAIN AREA; IMPEDING PEDESTRIANS PROHIBITED; WASTE RECEPTACLE REQUIRED ON STAND, CART, ETC.</catch_line>
 <order_by>12-1024</order_by>
 <text>
  <section prefix="(a)">	All vending controlled by the Private Use of Public Spaces Handbook as adopted by the Raleigh City Council on February 20, 2007, and as subsequently amended shall only be conducted pursuant to the terms of that document. Anyone vending without a permit or outside the parameters of the handbook relating to location, type of cart, product sold, or any other specification shall be guilty of a misdemeanor. The misdemeanor may be punished by a fine greater than fifty dollars ($50.00) as set out in N.C.G.S. 14-4. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(b)">	Except pursuant to a special event permit, it shall be unlawful to peddle in the streets of the City items other than foodstuffs prepared in conformity with applicable Wake County Health Regulations, fresh cut flowers, fruits, vegetables, dairy products, and original artworks and handicrafts produced by the peddler. If a special event permit is granted the peddler may also sell merchandise which is related to the event for the product has been granted. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(c)">
   <section prefix="(1)">	The vendor shall obtain an annual permit from the City after establishing that the vendor complies with all legal requirements for its operation; 
</section>
   <section prefix="(2)">	All equipment required for the operation and the operation itself is contained within the zero-emissions motorized vehicle;
</section>
   <section prefix="(3)">	The vendor may occupy the loading zone space at the end of the posted period for the loading zone space and shall remove all equipment and leave all loading zones no later than 11:00 p.m.; 
</section>
   <section prefix="(4)">	The vendor shall not use or permit customers to use the street. All vending transactions with customers shall occur at the curb; 
</section>
   <section prefix="(5)">	The vendor shall promptly remove any trash associated with its operation; 
</section>
   <section prefix="(6)">	The vehicle shall be no larger than shall have a gross vehicle weight when unloaded no greater than three thousand nine hundred (3,900) lbs. and the vehicle shall not extend beyond the boundaries of the commercial loading zone; 
</section>
   <section prefix="(7)">	The vendor shall hold the City, its officers, councilors, and employees harmless and indemnify them for any loss, liability, damage, and costs and expenses arising from its operations; and, 
</section>
   <section prefix="(8)">	No fixed-location business of a competing nature and no outdoor dining space is located within 50' of the loading zone parking space to be used by the vendor. 
</section>
  </section>
  <section prefix="(d)">	Provided further, it shall be unlawful for any person to erect, maintain or have any stand, cart or vehicle upon any street which impedes, endangers or interferes with the travel upon or use of the streets by the public. Each such stand, cart or vehicle shall be equipped with a waste receptacle and shall have rubber tires. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(e)">
   <section prefix="(1)">	A home occupation use permit for a home based business.
</section>
   <section prefix="(2)">	A food vending permit from Wake County.
</section>
   <section prefix="(3)">	A valid City of Raleigh business license. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(4)">	A scaled sketch plan or photographs showing proposed cart location, dimension, and details of surrounding streetscape elements, covering six (6) feet on all sides of the edge of the cart operation area including property lines, sidewalks, curb lines, lighting, trees indicating size, tree grates, planters, parking meters, benches, street signs, bus stops and fire hydrants. The cart operation area shall not exceed one hundred (100) square feet. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(5)">	A list of products to be sold.
</section>
   <section prefix="(6)">	Proof of a valid insurance policy that provides a minimum liability coverage of one million dollars ($1,000,000.00) with the City named as an additional insured. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(7)">	A written indemnity agreement that will hold harmless the City, its officers, and employees, for any loss or liability or damage, including costs, for bodily injury or property damage sustained by a person as a result of the negligent installation, use, or maintenance of a permitted space. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(8)">	A food permit from the N.C. Department of Agriculture if the applicant intends to sell baked goods or ice cream.
</section>
  </section>
  <section prefix="(f)">	Permit holders may be required to remove private materials or accessories to allow street, sidewalk, or utility access for maintenance operation or during approved special events. All permits issued pursuant to this section shall be suspended during a special event approved by the City Council. Carts are excluded within four hundred (400) feet of the edge of any special events area unless the permit holder is given permission from the event sponsor to set up within the designated event area. No more than three (3) permits per cart shall be issued to any cart owner. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(g)">
   <section prefix="(1)">	Carts must not locate in any area that impedes, endangers, or interferes with pedestrian or vehicular traffic.
</section>
   <section prefix="(2)">	Carts selling food products must be located at least fifty (50) feet from the entrance to any business selling food unless the owner of the other business gives written permission for the infringement of the no vending area. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(3)">	Carts must locate at least fifty (50) feet from any outdoor eating area.
</section>
   <section prefix="(4)">	Carts must be located at least two (2) feet from any curb.
</section>
   <section prefix="(5)">	Carts must not be locked or attached to trees or street furniture. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(6)">	Carts must maintain an unobstructed pedestrian corridor of a minimum of five (5) feet in width parallel to the street. On Fayetteville Street the minimum pedestrian corridor is seven (7) feet. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(7)">	No more than two (2) carts will be allowed on any block face.
</section>
  </section>
  <section prefix="(h)">
   <section prefix="(1)">	Carts must be non-motorized with operable wheels. Persons with disabilities may use a motorized system to propel the cart. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(2)">	All carts must be self contained with a waste receptacle. All equipment other than coolers must be contained on or with in the cart. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(3)">	A cart may not exceed six (6) feet in height and eight and one-half (8.5) feet in length and four (4) feet in width. Carts permitted prior to 2007 may continue to operate if they exceed any of these dimensions. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(4)">	Umbrellas or canopies must be attached to the cart and must not exceed eight (8) feet in height above grade. Maximum diameter of canopies and umbrellas shall not exceed six (6) feet and shall not interfere with pedestrian movement. No cart shall have more than two (2) umbrellas. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(5)">	Carts must be constructed of durable material and not plastic or wood may be visible. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(6)">	Carts must comply with all local, state, and federal rules regarding sanitation and protection of food from airborne contamination.
</section>
   <section prefix="(7)">	All signage on carts shall comply with the Raleigh Sign Ordinance. No free standing signage is permitted. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(8)">	Sales of goods and merchandise are limited to food and beverage, fresh cut flowers, or original artwork and handicrafts produced by the vendor. All items for sale must be confined to the cart. Food vendors may place a maximum of three (3) coolers within their containment area so long as the coolers are neatly stacked to avoid visual clutter. No generators may be used at any time. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(9)">	A vendor may maintain one chair for his own use. No public seating is allowed. Pushcarts may not be stored, parked, or left overnight on any City property. 
(10)	Carts may only be operated between the hours of 6:00 a.m. and 3:00 a.m. Cleanup and removal of the cart must be completed by 3:30 a.m. The operator must be present at all times and must have a valid permit on his person or on the cart at all times. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(11)">	Permits are not transferrable.
</section>
   <section prefix="(12)">	The operator is responsible for all waste and trash removal. The containment area must be kept clear of grease, trash, paper, cups or cans associated with the operation. No liquid waste or grease is to be disposed of in tree pits or onto the sidewalks, streets or other public places. 
</section>
  </section>
  <section prefix="(i)">	Any street vending performed that is not in compliance with these regulations is illegal. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(j)">	A permit is revoked if the operator receives three (3) citations, either civil, criminal or combination thereof during any calendar year. 
(Code 1959 , §9-12; Ord. No. 1980-393, §§5, 6, 6-3-80; Ord. No. 1989-441, §1, 10-3-89; Ord. No. 2010-773, §1, 8-3-10; Ord. No. 2010-815, §1, 12-7-10; Ord. No. 2011-835, §1, 2-1-11; Ord. No. 2012-87, §1, 7-3-12) 
</section>
 </text>
</law>
