<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="Division" identifier="II" order_by="2" level="1">Division II - Planning and Development</unit>
  <unit label="part" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="2">PART 8 - PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit>
  <unit label="chapter" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="3">CHAPTER 2. - WATER AND SEWER SERVICE</unit>
  <unit label="article" identifier="B" order_by="B" level="4">ARTICLE B. - WATER AND SEWER EXTENSION POLICIES</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="8-2092" order_by="8-2092" level="5">Sec. 8-2092. - ACREAGE FEES IMPOSED ON ALL EXTENSIONS.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>8-2092</section_number>
 <catch_line>ACREAGE FEES IMPOSED ON ALL EXTENSIONS.</catch_line>
 <order_by>8-2092</order_by>
 <text>
  <section prefix="(a)">
   <section prefix="(1)"> The acreage fee charge for non-residential uses developed in residential zoning districts will be based upon the fee table above. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(2)"> If the land in these districts is actually developed for non-residential uses, the fees will be the lesser of either the charges stated above or the charges stated below based on the actual water tap size utilized for the property. 
Water Tap Size
(inches)	Water Acreage Fee
(per tap)	Sewer Acreage Fee
(per tap)
 ¾	$ 1,688.00	$ 1,688.00
1	2,810.00	2,810.00
1½	5,592.00	5,592.00
2	8,943.00	8,943.00
4	23,435.00	23,435.00
6	53,640.00	53,640.00
8	85,794.00	85,794.00
10 inch and greater	Must be individually quoted by City 
 
Following the last working day in June, all fees stated herein shall be adjusted annually based on &quot;Engineering News Record Construction Cost Index&quot;, as published in December. After the fees are indexed, the fees shall be rounded to the nearest dollar. 
Acreage fees collected to reimburse for major mains shall be assigned to the same acreage fee area it was collected from, as may be amended. Such funds shall remain available for reimbursement of major mains installed in that same area, as may be amended, until the first day of January following ten (10) years after its collection. The water acreage fee areas and the sewer acreage fee areas are shown on maps on file in the City Clerk's office. 
</section>
  </section>
  <section prefix="(b)">	The acreage fees charged public schools shall be limited as follows: 
Elementary schools: Pay fee for a maximum of four (4) acres. 
Junior high schools: Pay fee for a maximum of seven (7) acres. 
Senior high schools: Pay fee for a maximum of ten (10) acres. 
Parks and recreation facilities: Maximum of three (3) acres for each connection up to a maximum fee based on seven (7) acres for single park site and if a subsequent connection is made, the same criteria would be applicable with maximum fee for site based on cumulative total of seven (7) acres. 
Provided, however, that if any land so subject to the provisions of this paragraph that acreage fees are not chargeable therefor is ever conveyed to a grantee other than a school board or used for any other than school purposes, it shall be subject to the then-applicable acreage fees without limitation. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(c)">	The owner of a tract of residential land, or of land in an area zoned for residential use which is owned, occupied, and used by a nonprofit organization as a private recreation area containing more than three (3) acres, who desires to make one (1) tap on to the utility systems of the City but who has not, and does not, desire to subdivide his property into building lots at the time the tap on is made, may tap on to such systems at the rates of charge herein contained for three (3) acres of land. The owner of a tract of residential land or of land in an area zoned for residential use which is owned and occupied at the time of utility connection by the owner as his dwelling place or the dwelling place of only his family (e.g., a father, mother, and one (1) or more unmarried children, or dependents physically residing in the same structure or group of structures) containing more than two (2) acres, who desires to make one (1) tap-on to the utility systems of the City but who has not and does not, desire to subdivide his property into building lots at the time the tap-on is made, may tap onto such systems at the rates charged herein containing two (2) acres of land. A charge for services to the remaining land shall be made when services are extended to that land. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(d)">	When no acreage fee reimbursement contract exists within an acreage fee area and an individual, developer, or subdivider has installed a major water or major sewer main that would be eligible for reimbursement, that individual, developer, or subdivider may request that the City credit the reimbursable value of that major main to payment of prevailing acreage fees, on designated parcels of land located within that acreage fee area in lieu of entering into a reimbursement agreement for said main. Prior to receiving credit for such dedication or assignment, the dedicator of the major mains shall waive in writing any right to a reimbursement contract from the City as now or hereafter allowed. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(e)">	The owner of a mobile restroom unit shall pay a special acreage fee of fifty dollars ($50.00) per plumbing fixture within the unit for each water and sewer. 
(Res. 1961-233; Res. 1964-404; Res. 1970-976; Res. 1972-659; Res. 1973-773; Ord. No. 1979-186, 8-21-79; Ord. No. 1981-670, §1, 5-19-81; Ord. No. 1984-338, §§2, 3, 4-17-84; Ord. No. 1984-470, §1, 12-18-84; Ord. No. 1985-543, §13, 4-16-85; Ord. No. 1985-585, §1, 6-18-85; Ord. No. 1985-628, §1, 9-3-85; Ord. No. 1985-681, §1, 12-3-85; Ord. No. 1986-754, §1, 4-1-86; Ord. No. 1986-860, §1, 10-7-86; Ord. No. 1987-955, §1, 4-21-87; Ord. No. 1988-145, §1, 4-19-88; Ord. No. 1988-291-TC-327, §13, 12-13-88; Ord. No. 1989-375, §1, 6-6-89; Ord. No. 1989-418, §1, 9-5-89; Ord. No. 1990-599, §1, 6-19-90; Ord. No. 1991-718, §1, 2-5-91; Ord. No. 1991-878, 7-16-91; Ord. No. 1992-966, §1, 5-5-92; Ord. No. 1993-199, §1, 6-1-93; Ord. No. 1994-398, §1, 5-17-94; Ord. No. 1995-624, §1, 5-2-95; Ord. No. 1997-112, §1, 5-20-97; Ord. No. 1998-258, §1, 1-6-98; Ord. No. 1998-334, §1, 6-2-98; Ord. No. 1999-545, §1, 4-20-99; Ord. No. 2000-795, §1, 5-16-00; Ord. No. 2001-994, §1, 5-1-01; Ord. No. 2002-195, §1, 5-7-02; Ord. No. 203-436, §1, 5-6-03; Ord. No. 2004-620, §1, 5-4-04; Ord. No. 2005-823, §1, 5-17-05; Ord. No. 2006-13, §1, 5-2-06; Ord. No. 2007-165-TC-299, §1, TC-1-07, 2-6-07; Ord. No. 2007-223, §1, 5-1-07, eff. 7-1-07; Ord. No. 2008-376, §1, 4-15-08, eff. 7-1-08; Ord. No. 2009-554, §1, 3-17-09, eff. 7-1-09; Ord. No. 2010-716, §1, 4-6-10, eff. 7-1-10; Ord. No. 2011-882, §1, 5-17-11, eff. 7-1-11; Ord. No. 2012-52, §1, 5-14-12, eff. 7-1-12; Ord. No. 2012-81, §3, 6-19-12, eff. 7-1-12) 
Cross reference: Collection of acreage fees, §10-6081(e). 
</section>
 </text>
</law>
