<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="Division" identifier="II" order_by="2" level="1">Division II - Planning and Development</unit>
  <unit label="part" identifier="13" order_by="13" level="2">PART 13 - OFFENSES [1]</unit>
  <unit label="chapter" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="3">CHAPTER 4. - REGULATION OF SECURITY AND FIRE ALARM SYSTEMS [4]</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="13-4006" order_by="13-4006" level="4">Sec. 13-4006. - FINES.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>13-4006</section_number>
 <catch_line>FINES.</catch_line>
 <order_by>13-4006</order_by>
 <text>
  <section prefix="(a)">	It shall be unlawful for any person to dump or deposit from trucks, trailers or other vehicles any waste, refuse, garbage, ashes, rubbish, building rubbish, combustible refuse, noncombustible refuse or industrial waste (hereinafter in this section referred to as waste material) upon any of the sanitary landfills of the City except as herein provided. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(b)">	Only waste material generated within the Raleigh City limits or authorized by contract with the City of Raleigh may be deposited in the City landfill. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(c)">	Persons hauling waste material generated from commercial, industrial and all other uses shall be charged disposal fees of twenty-eight dollars ($28.00) per ton for wastes. For wastes other than white goods there shall be a minimum charge, based on the prorated weight of one-half (0.5) ton for each transaction. The disposal fee for white goods shall be prorated based on actual weight. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(d)">	No fee shall be charged for disposal of scrap tires from any source, except as permitted by state law for (1) new tires disposed of by the manufacturer because they do not meet the manufacturer's standards, and (2) tires delivered without an accompanying certificate required by G.S. 130A-309.58 indicating that the tires originated within North Carolina. Where fees for tire disposal are permitted by state law, the fee charged shall be set according to the then current cost of disposal to the City. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(e)">	Persons, businesses, or organizations shall not be charged a disposal fee for waste collected under contract with the City, but shall be charged a disposal fee of twenty-eight dollars ($28.00) per ton for all other wastes. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(f)">	Each load, or part thereof, of waste material dumped, deposited or delivered to any of the City's landfills shall be weighed by an authorized agent of the City as it enters and leaves landfill. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(g)">	It shall be unlawful for any person to pay or for the supervisor and/or employees at the landfill to receive anything of value for the privileges accorded by this section, or for the supervisor of any landfill to receive any waste material except in conformity herewith, except as provided for in above sections. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(h)">	The Solid Waste Services Director shall require all users of the landfill that are levied fees to be registered prior to dumping of refuse. A report on names of users to be charged along with fees will be provided to the Revenue Collector for collecting such fees. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(i)">	This section shall not apply to employees of City departments using City equipment in the performance of their assigned duties. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(j)">	Persons using the City's landfill, in addition, shall comply with all other reasonable regulations promulgated by the City Manager and/or approved by the City Council. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(k)">
   <section prefix="(1)">	Hours open to public: 7:00 a.m. to 3:45 p.m., Monday through Saturday. Closed Sundays and holidays.
</section>
   <section prefix="(2)">	Prohibited waste materials: 
a.	All liquid wastes. 
b.	Hazardous solid wastes (includes but is not limited to explosives, radioactive materials, hot ashes, burning or smoldering materials, and groundwater contaminants). 
c.	Automotive vehicles and large parts thereof.
d.	Large metal fabrications and appliances.
e.	Building, roadway, drainage or other construction or demolition debris, unless it is reduced to its smallest practicable sizes.
f.	Tree trunks and limbs greater than six (6) inches in diameter and six (6) feet in length.
g.	Human bodies or parts thereof and/or pathological material.
h.	All white goods (to include inoperative and discarded refrigerators, ranges, water heaters, freezers and other similar domestic and commercial large appliances). 
i.	All lead-acid batteries.
j.	All tree trimmings, hedge cuttings, or similar materials (yard waste). 
k.	All yard trash as described in G.S. 130A-309.10. 
l.	Aluminum cans.
</section>
   <section prefix="(3)">	Users must comply with &quot;Rules and Regulations Providing Standards for Solid Waste Disposal&quot; as adopted by the North Carolina State Board of Health. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(4)">	Users must be registered with the Solid Waste Services Director and be able to identify sources of wastes delivered to the landfill. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(5)">	All loads of wastes shall be covered or otherwise loaded and secured to prevent contents from falling, leaking, spilling or blowing. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(6)">	Vehicles and containers containing garbage shall be covered and leakproof. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(7)">	All vehicles shall be weighed before and after dumping their loads. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(8)">	Only the vehicle operator and one additional person will be permitted to accompany each vehicle to the dumping site. No children (minors) will be authorized beyond the weigh station. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(9)">	Dumping will be permitted at designated areas only.
(10)	City personnel and equipment will not assist in unloading vehicles or containers. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(11)">	City personnel and equipment will not assist in extricating disabled vehicles unless the vehicle operators execute appropriate waivers of liability. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(12)">	The following are specifically prohibited: 
a.	Fires or other burning.
b.	Scavenging and loitering.
c.	Dumping of wastes after 1:00 p.m., which contain foul odors (includes but is not limited to soy bean hulls). 
</section>
  </section>
  <section prefix="(l)">
   <section prefix="(1)">	For the first disposal, a written notice will be issued. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(2)">	For the second disposal, a total charge will be made equal to two (2) times the disposal fee set forth in this section (the surcharge being equal to the disposal fee). 
</section>
   <section prefix="(3)">	For the third and any subsequent disposals, a total charge equal to three (3) times the disposal fee set forth in this section (the surcharge being equal to twice the disposal fee). 
</section>
  </section>
  <section prefix="(m)">	Anyone dumping or depositing yard trash into any City-operated sanitary landfill shall remove such trash immediately upon being requested to do so by a representative of the City. If the person depositing any such trash fails to remove it upon request of the City, the trash will be removed by City forces and deposited in the yard waste center. The person who illegally deposited the yard trash shall be billed by the City for its cost in removing the waste from the sanitary landfill, for the cost of transporting the trash to the yard waste center, and for the standard tipping fee for a load of the requisite size to accommodate the removal. 
In addition to any other penalties and remedies available hereunder, any person depositing yard trash into a sanitary landfill of the City shall be subject to a one hundred dollar ($100.00) civil penalty for the initial deposit and a fifty dollar ($50.00) per day civil penalty for each day the trash remains in the sanitary landfill after its removal has been ordered. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(n)">	Anyone dumping or depositing aluminum cans into any City-operated sanitary landfill shall remove such cans upon request from a representative of the City. If the person depositing such cans fails to remove them at the request of the City, the cans will be removed by the City. The person who deposited the cans in the landfill shall be billed by the City for the cost of removing the cans from the landfill, and for the cost of delivering the cans for recycling, and for any cost of cleaning or emptying the cans to make them acceptable for recycling. 
In addition to any other penalties and remedies available hereunder, any person depositing aluminum cans into a sanitary landfill of the City shall be subject to a one hundred dollar ($100.00) civil penalty for the initial deposit and a fifty dollar ($50.00) per day penalty for each day the cans remain in the sanitary landfill after their removal has been ordered. 
(Ord. No. 1998-454, ยง9, 11-4-98) 
Editor's note: Subsection (k)(2)j was added by Ord. No. 1992-36, effective Jan. 1, 1993. That addition required the renumbering of the provisions added by Ord. No. 1992-104 from (k)(2)j to (k)(2)l. A new subsection (l) was added by ยง1 of Ord. No. 1992-68, ยง5 declared the surtax given in paragraphs (2) and (3) of that subsection effective July 1, 1993. That addition necessitated the renumbering of the provisions added by Ord. No. 1992-104 from ยง7-2007(l) to (m).  
</section>
 </text>
</law>
