<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="division" identifier="I" order_by="1" level="1">Division I - Charter</unit>
  <unit label="article" identifier="VI" order_by="6" level="2">ARTICLE VI. - MUNICIPAL FUNCTIONS</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="6.41" order_by="6.41" level="3">Sec. 6.41 - CARE FUND FOR CEMETERIES.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>I-VI-6.41</section_number>
 <catch_line>CARE FUND FOR CEMETERIES.</catch_line>
 <order_by>6.41</order_by>
 <section prefix="text">
The City Council is authorized to create a fund to be known as the perpetual care fund for the cemetery or cemeteries, for the purpose of perpetually caring for and beautifying the cemetery or cemeteries, and said fund shall be kept by the City as is provided for bequests and gifts for cemetery purposes; and the City Council may make contracts with plat or space owners in the cemetery or cemeteries, obligating the City to keep up and maintain said lots or spaces, in perpetuity, upon payment of such sum or sums as may be fixed by the City Council; and the City Council is further authorized and empowered to accept gifts and bequests for such purposes, or upon such other trusts as the donors may prescribe; and the City Council is authorized to set aside for said perpetual care fund an amount not exceeding twenty-five (25) per cent of the proceeds of sale of cemetery lots. The principal of said funds so appropriated by the City Council for the caring for the cemetery or cemeteries shall be held by the City Council for caring for and beautifying the cemetery or cemeteries, and improving the same. The income from the said fund heretofore or hereafter made shall be used for such purpose of carrying out contracts with the individual plat or space owners for perpetual care of individual plats and spaces. Any gift heretofore or hereafter made to and received by the City, or any of its officers, shall be held and used as a sacred trust fund for the purpose and upon the conditions named in such gifts or bequests, and any and all such funds shall be kept or invested separate and shall not be used for any other purpose, or by the City in its other affairs. The City Treasurer shall keep a separate account of the cemetery funds, and a still further separate account of all special gifts or bequests made by persons for and in connection with the cemetery or cemeteries, and particular lots therein. The City Council shall have the power to make rules and regulations and adopt ordinances for the carrying out of the duties imposed by this section. 
</section>
</law>
