<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="Division" identifier="II" order_by="2" level="1">Division II - Planning and Development</unit>
  <unit label="part" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">PART 12 - LICENSING AND REGULATION</unit>
  <unit label="chapter" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="3">CHAPTER 2. - BUSINESSES AND TRADES</unit>
  <unit label="article" identifier="E" order_by="E" level="4">ARTICLE E. - MASSAGES [6]</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="12-2135" order_by="12-2135" level="5">Sec. 12-2135. - REVOCATION OF MASSAGE BUSINESS OPERATOR'S LICENSE.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>12-2135</section_number>
 <catch_line>REVOCATION OF MASSAGE BUSINESS OPERATOR'S LICENSE.</catch_line>
 <order_by>12-2135</order_by>
 <text>
  <section prefix="(a)">
   <section prefix="(1)">	That the licensee has violated any provision of this chapter;
</section>
   <section prefix="(2)">	That the licensee, or any agent of the licensee, employs or permits to be on the premises of the applicant's massage business any person practicing the business or profession of massage who has not been licensed by the State of North Carolina or who has not been issued the regulatory license required by this article, or whose license under this article or under North Carolina General Statutes has been revoked or is currently suspended; 
</section>
   <section prefix="(3)">	That the licensee, or the legal or beneficial owner of any interest in the licensee, is convicted of any crime involving sexual misconduct, including but not limited to a violation of: G.S. 14-177—14-202.4 (offenses against public morality and decency); G.S. 14-203—14-208 (prostitution); §§13-3002 and 13-2015 of this Code, a Federal prostitution statute; or any other governmental units' regulations of massages; 
</section>
   <section prefix="(4)">	That any current employee of the licensee is convicted of any felony in connection with his or her employment, or is convicted of any crime involving sexual misconduct, including, but not limited to, a violation of G.S. 14-177—14-202.4 (offenses against public morality and decency); G.S. 14-203—14-208 (prostitution); §§13-3002 and 13-2015 of this Code; any Federal prostitution statute; or any governmental units' regulations of massage; 
</section>
   <section prefix="(5)">	That the licensee violates any zoning, building, or fire prevention ordinance, or if exempted from building or fire prevention inspections, performs massage to a client or for a fee within the home or allows the public to enter the home in connection with the massage business; 
</section>
   <section prefix="(6)">	That the licensed business is conducted or allowed to be conducted in a manner constituting a public nuisance; or
</section>
   <section prefix="(7)">	That the licensee has failed to supervise an employee and the employee has, in connection with the massage business, been convicted of a violation of G.S. 14-177—14-202.4 (offenses against public morality and decency), G.S. 14-203—14-208 (prostitution); §§13-3002 and 13-2015 of this Code, a Federal prostitution statute, or any other governmental units' regulations of massages. 
</section>
  </section>
  <section prefix="(b)">	A license issued pursuant to this article is void if the licensee moves or ceases operating a massage business at the location required to be stated in the application for license pursuant to this article. A licensee may transfer the massage business license to a new location once in any calendar year upon payment of a fifty-dollar ($50.00) nonrefundable transfer fee and upon confirmation from the inspections division that the new location complies with all zoning and building regulations and ordinances, and from the Fire Department that the new location complies with all laws relating to fire prevention. A licensee who, consistent with zoning regulations, lawfully operates the massage business out of the licensee's home and who signs a statement under oath that the licensee will not perform massage within the home or allow the public to enter the home in connection with the massage business is not required to submit to a building or fire prevention inspection. 
(Ord. No. 2001-935, §3, 2-6-01) 
</section>
 </text>
</law>
