<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="Division" identifier="II" order_by="2" level="1">Division II - Planning and Development</unit>
  <unit label="part" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">PART 12 - LICENSING AND REGULATION</unit>
  <unit label="chapter" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="3">CHAPTER 1. - STREETS AND PUBLIC WAYS</unit>
  <unit label="article" identifier="B" order_by="B" level="4">ARTICLE B. - STREET USE AND CLEANLINESS</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="12-1040" order_by="12-1040" level="5">Sec. 12-1040. - DEPOSITING TRASH ON STREET.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>12-1040</section_number>
 <catch_line>DEPOSITING TRASH ON STREET.</catch_line>
 <order_by>12-1040</order_by>
 <text>
No person shall throw, drop or deposit, or cause to be thrown, dropped or deposited on any street, avenue, alley, highway, footway, sidewalk, park, or other public place or space in the City, any waste (including but not limited to, refuse, garbage, ashes, rubbish, building rubbish, dead animals, putrescible matter, paper, drinking cups, broken glass, tacks, brush, grass, weeds, and anything injurious to health); provided, however, building rubbish and material used in building, construction, repair, remodeling and excavating operations may be deposited in the aforesaid places when permitted by and in accordance with other applicable ordinances. If any person, while transporting or hauling, or causing to be transported or hauled, such rubbish or material, or earth, excavation, coal or other material, shall throw, drop or deposit, or cause to be thrown, dropped or deposited, such rubbish or material from the body of the vehicle, in violation of the provisions of this subsection, such person must daily clean up and remove such rubbish or material in a manner satisfactory to the Director of Public Works, failing which the Department of Public Works may clean up and remove such rubbish and material, and the City may collect the cost of such cleaning up and removal from such person. 
(Ord. No. 1998-454, ยง12, 11-4-98) 
</text>
</law>
