<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="Division" identifier="II" order_by="2" level="1">Division II - Planning and Development</unit>
  <unit label="part" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">PART 12 - LICENSING AND REGULATION</unit>
  <unit label="chapter" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="3">CHAPTER 2. - BUSINESSES AND TRADES</unit>
  <unit label="article" identifier="B" order_by="B" level="4">ARTICLE B. - VEHICLES FOR HIRE</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="12-2082" order_by="12-2082" level="5">Sec. 12-2082. - APPLICATION.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>12-2082</section_number>
 <catch_line>APPLICATION.</catch_line>
 <order_by>12-2082</order_by>
 <text>
  <section prefix="(a)">
   <section prefix="(1)">	The full name, age, date of birth, place of birth and address of the applicant.
</section>
   <section prefix="(2)">	The length of time of the applicant's residence in the City and in the State and whether or not he is a citizen of the United States. Citizens of the United States shall provide a social security card and non-citizens shall provide a current alien registration card. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(3)">	The applicant's full personal description; including his height, weight, sex, race, color of eyes, color of hair, complexion, body and facial marks and defects, if any. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(4)">	The applicant's physical condition including hearing and eyesight and the extent of his present and past due to intoxicating liquors, alcoholic beverages and narcotic and barbiturate drugs. 
The applicant will produce valid evidence that he has successfully passed a drug test prior to employment or affiliation with a taxicab/vehicle for hire company. If the applicant has failed the drug test, he is not eligible to apply for a taxicab/vehicle for hire driver's permit, for a one-year period following the drug test. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(5)">	The applicant's previous places of employment for the five (5) years immediately preceding the date of his application for a driver's permit and his previous experience in driving taxicabs and other vehicles for hire carrying passengers. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(6)">	The applicant's complete record of criminal citations (including those for traffic violations), arrests and convictions.
a.	Have no more than seven (7) accrued points for motor vehicle violations pursuant to §12-2091; six (6) during the previous three (3) years or any comparable provision of the law of another state. The taxicab inspector will review the driving records of all applicants who have eight (8) or more points on their current driving records. The issuance of a taxicab driving permit will be at the taxicab inspector's discretion based on the totality of the driving record. 
b.	No application for a driver's permit shall be accepted from an applicant who has criminal charges pending against him at the time of application. For purposes of this subsection, pending criminal charges shall not include traffic infractions. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(7)">	The number and date of issuance of the applicant's state driver's license.
</section>
   <section prefix="(8)">	The number and date of issuance of the applicant's required state license.
</section>
   <section prefix="(9)">	Such other information as the taxicab inspector or City Council may require. 
</section>
  </section>
  <section prefix="(b)">
   <section prefix="(1)">	Full fingerprints of the applicant.
</section>
   <section prefix="(2)">	Four (4) front view photographs of the applicant of such sizes as specified by the Chief of Police or his designee.
</section>
   <section prefix="(3)">	A certificate of a physician in the City stating that the applicant is not afflicted with any disease, physical disability, hearing deficit, vision deficit, or any other physical affliction which would materially impair his ability to drive a taxicab in a safe manner and in a manner that will not endanger the health of the public. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(4)">	A current health certificate issued by the Board of Health.
</section>
   <section prefix="(5)">	The sum of fifty dollars ($50.00) and an additional amount to be determined by the Chief of Police or his designee to cover the cost of the fingerprint check. Both fees are non-refundable. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(6)">	On forms provided by the taxicab inspector: 
a.	A testimonial from his last employer;
b.	A letter of introduction from his prospective employer; and
c.	Affidavits of his good character from two (2) reputable citizens of the City who have known him personally and have observed his conduct for one year next preceding the date of his application. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(7)">	Each operating permit holder must require its taxicab drivers to enroll in and successfully complete within ten (10) days from the date of the issuance of the driver's permit a training course conducted by the taxicab inspector or his/her designee. All current drivers of taxicabs must be in compliance with this section within two (2) years of the effective date of this article. 
</section>
  </section>
  <section prefix="(c)">	It shall be unlawful for any applicant knowingly to make a false statement or knowingly to give false information on his application for a driver's permit. Any material false statement or false information made or given by an applicant in applying for a driver's permit shall invalidate the permit issue to such applicant. 
(Code 1959 , §22-44; Ord. No. 1988-220, §7, 7-19-88; Ord. No. 1999-691, §§8—11, 11-16-99; Ord. No. 2002-332, § 1, 11-19-02; Ord. No. 2003-390, §3, 2-18-03; Ord. No. 2009-671, §§28—31, 11-3-09) 
</section>
 </text>
</law>
