<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="division" identifier="I" order_by="1" level="1">Division I - Charter</unit>
  <unit label="article" identifier="VI" order_by="6" level="2">ARTICLE VI. - MUNICIPAL FUNCTIONS</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="6.22" order_by="6.22" level="3">Sec. 6.22 - POWERS AND DUTIES OF CHIEF OF POLICE AND MEMBERS OF DEPARTMENT.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>I-VI-6.22</section_number>
 <catch_line>POWERS AND DUTIES OF CHIEF OF POLICE AND MEMBERS OF DEPARTMENT.</catch_line>
 <order_by>6.22</order_by>
 <section prefix="text">
  <section prefix="(a)">	The Chief of Police, acting under the Director of Public Safety, shall have the supervision and control of the police force, and it shall be his duty to report to the Director of Public Safety any failure of duty on the part of any member of the police force. It shall be the duty of the Chief of Police to see that all laws and ordinances of the City are enforced and to do all such things as may be required of him by ordinances adopted by the City Council or by the Director of Public Safety. The Chief of Police and each member of the police force shall have the same power and authority as are vested in sheriffs and constables for the preservation of the peace of the City; such power and authority to be exercised by them not only in the corporate limits, but within all territory extending one mile in all directions from and beyond the corporate limits of the City (and on any rights-of-way, easements, or property of the City without the corporate limits). They shall execute all process legally directed to them by any court and in the execution thereof shall have the same powers that sheriffs and constables have in the discharge of like duties. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(b)">	The City Council may make rules and regulations for the government and direction of the police officers of the City or may delegate such power to the Director of Public Safety. The City Council may require the entire police force to wear badges, and to be so armed and uniformed as to be readily recognized by the public as peace officers; provided, that the Director of Public Safety, or the Chief of Police, when either deems it necessary, may authorize any such officer to be on duty in plain clothes. The police of the City shall have power to do whatever may be necessary to preserve the good order and peace of the City and secure the inhabitants from personal violence and their property from loss or injuries. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(c)">	When funds shall have been appropriated for the purpose, and when considered expedient and in the public interest, the Chief of Police, subject to the approval of the City Manager, may employ temporarily, for a period of time not to exceed twelve (12) months, persons to obtain information regarding criminal activity within the City; provided, however, that there shall not be any re-employment of any such person at any time within a period of thirty (30) days immediately following the termination of a previous term of such temporary employment; provided, further, that such persons so employed may, but shall not be required to, take and subscribe the same oath required of regular police officers of the City and if so sworn shall have all of the powers, authority and duties of regular police officers of the City; provided, further, that such persons so employed shall not be subject to the Civil Service Act applicable to policemen and firemen of the City. Such persons so employed shall be subject to the orders and direction of the Director of Public Safety, Chief of Police and the City Manager. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(d)">	The Director of Public Safety, Chief of Police, and each member of the police force, before entering upon the discharge of the duties of his office, shall be required to take and subscribe before the Mayor, or some other officers authorized to administer oaths in such cases, the oath prescribed for public officers, and an oath that he will faithfully and impartially discharge the duties of his office according to law, which said oath shall be filed with the City Clerk and entered in the book with the oaths of the members of the City Council and other officers of the City. 
) 
</section>
 </section>
 <history>(S.L. 1957, Ch. 107, ยง1; S.L. 1973, Ch. 319, ยง1(r)</history>
</law>
