<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="Division" identifier="II" order_by="2" level="1">Division II - Planning and Development</unit>
  <unit label="part" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="2">PART 8 - PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit>
  <unit label="chapter" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="3">CHAPTER 2. - WATER AND SEWER SERVICE</unit>
  <unit label="article" identifier="E" order_by="E" level="4">ARTICLE E. - WATER CONSERVATION PLAN [6]</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="8-2176" order_by="8-2176" level="5">Sec. 8-2176. - VOLUNTARY WATER USE MEASURES.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>8-2176</section_number>
 <catch_line>VOLUNTARY WATER USE MEASURES.</catch_line>
 <order_by>8-2176</order_by>
 <text>
  <section prefix="(a)">	Outdoor Water Uses: 
1.	It is recommended that all irrigation systems which use water from the public water supply should be operated in the following manner: 
a.	Properties with ODD numbered addresses water lawns and landscapes on TUESDAY, THURSDAY and SATURDAY.
b.	Properties with EVEN numbered addresses water lawns and landscapes on WEDNESDAY, FRIDAY and SUNDAY.
Automatic or non-automatic irrigation systems should only be operated between the hours of 12:00:01 a.m. and 10:00 a.m. and hose end sprinklers should be operated only between the hours of 6:00 a.m. and 10:00 a.m. and also 6:00 p.m. and 10:00 p.m. No automatic or non-automatic irrigation systems or hose end sprinklers should be operated on MONDAY. Automatic or non-automatic irrigation systems and hose end sprinklers should be operated in a manner to prevent water waste so as to avoid watering impervious surfaces such as streets, parking lots, driveways and sidewalks at all times. 
2.	Check for plumbing leaks. A single dripping faucet can waste hundreds, even thousands, of gallons per year. Most water leaks are easy to detect and repair with basic plumbing skills and a few simple tools. 
3.	Have soil tested by the North Carolina Department of Agronomy/Soil Testing Section. Most yards in this region are composed of granite soils. They need lime more than they need fertilizer. 
4.	Plant native trees and shrubs. The North Carolina State University Cooperative Extension Service has excellent suggestions for home gardeners. Use mulch around shrubs and garden plants to reduce evaporation. Mix the turf areas with shaded areas to reduce irrigation demands. 
5.	Let the grass grow taller in hot weather by raising your lawn mower cutting height. Longer grass blades help shade each other, reduce evaporation, and inhibit weed growth. 
6.	Water slowly and thoroughly during cool, windless hours to prevent water loss from evaporation.
7.	Be attentive if using a hose and sprinkler, consider setting an alarm or the oven timer as a reminder to move the hose and sprinkler as needed. 
8.	Use a rain gauge. One (1) inch of water per week will keep lawns green throughout the summer.
9.	Water should be applied slowly to achieve deep penetration and prevent water run-off.
10.	Do not water impervious surfaces such as streets, parking lots, driveways and sidewalks.
11.	Install a drip irrigation system for watering gardens, trees, and shrubs. Drip systems are very efficient because they provide a slow, steady trickle of water to plants at their roots through a network of hidden pipes and hoses. 
12.	Use properly treated reuse water for irrigation as an alternative water source. Raleigh's water conservation rules do not regulate the amount of reuse water and therefore any amount can be used during any mandatory water conservation stage. Contact the Raleigh Public Utilities Department for information regarding reuse water availability. 
13.	Capture rain water in cisterns and rain barrels. The average rainfall in the Raleigh area is about forty-eight (48) inches per year. Run-off from the roof of a typical two thousand five hundred (2,500) square foot home is about seventy-five thousand (75,000) gallons a year. Raleigh encourages customers to capture rainwater and use it on the landscape. 
14.	Consider the amount of water being used and look for ways to use less whenever possibly. Do not leave water running - use spring loaded or other automatic shut-off devices on hoses or outdoor faucets. 
15.	Use commercial vehicle washing facilities, especially those which have been certified by Raleigh as water conserving facilities, instead of washing vehicles at home. 
16.	Use a broom or blower to remove dust, dirt, leaves and other debris from sidewalks, driveways, porches and decks rather than water. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(b)">	Indoor Water Uses: 
1.	Thaw frozen food in your refrigerator or microwave instead of using running water. Wash fruits and vegetables with a vegetable brush in a basin or bowl instead of using running water. 
2.	Scrape or wipe, rather than rinse, dishes before loading into the dishwasher. Wash only full loads. Consider replacing old dishwasher with a water and energy saving model. 
3.	Wash only full loads of laundry or use the appropriate water level or load size selection on the washing machine. Presoak heavily soiled items. Use detergent sparingly in order to avoid rinsing more than normal cycle. Consider purchasing a high efficiency washing machine to save laundry water and energy. 
4.	Install low-flow toilets, faucet aerators, and low-flow showerheads.
5.	Leaky toilet can waste two hundred (200) gallons of water per day. To detect leaks in a toilet, add a few drops of food coloring to the tank water. Do not flush. Wait a few minutes. The toilet is leaking if the colored water appears in the bowl. 
6.	Commercial and industrial customers not otherwise regulated as a major water user should review their water uses and should consider implementing industry specific best management water conservation practices. 
7.	Check for leaks in toilets, faucets, shower heads and any other plumbing fixtures and repair these leaks immediately.
(Ord. No. 2007-235, ยง1, 5-15-07; Ord. No. 2010-793, ยง4, 10-19-10; Ord. No. 2012-48, ยง2, 5-14-12) 
</section>
 </text>
</law>
