<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="Division" identifier="II" order_by="2" level="1">Division II - Planning and Development</unit>
  <unit label="part" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="2">PART 8 - PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit>
  <unit label="chapter" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="3">CHAPTER 2. - WATER AND SEWER SERVICE</unit>
  <unit label="article" identifier="C" order_by="C" level="4">ARTICLE C. - USE OF SANITARY SEWER SYSTEM [4]</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="8-2124" order_by="8-2124" level="5">Sec. 8-2124. - SURCHARGES.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>8-2124</section_number>
 <catch_line>SURCHARGES.</catch_line>
 <order_by>8-2124</order_by>
 <text>
  <section prefix="(a)">
   <section prefix="(1)">	BOD greater than three hundred (300) mg/l and/or sixty-three (63) pounds. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(2)">	COD greater than five hundred (500) mg/l and/or one hundred four (104) pounds.
</section>
   <section prefix="(3)">	TSS greater than two hundred fifty (250) mg/l and/or fifty-two (52) pounds.
</section>
   <section prefix="(4)">	TN greater than thirty (30) mg/l and/or six (6) pounds.
</section>
   <section prefix="(5)">	TP greater than five (5) mg/l and/or one (1) pound.
</section>
   <section prefix="(6)">	F.O.G. greater than three hundred (300) mg/l and/or sixty-three (63) pounds.
</section>
  </section>
  <section prefix="(b)">
   <section prefix="(1)">	The volume of flow used in determining the total discharge of waste water for payment of user charges and surcharges shall be based on the following; 
a.	Metered water consumption as shown in the records of meter readings maintained by the City; or 
b.	If required by the City or at the individual discharger's option, other flow monitoring devices which measure the actual volume of waste water discharged to the sewer. Such devices shall be accessible and safely located, and the measuring system shall be installed in accordance with plans approved by the City. The metering system shall be installed and maintained at the user's expense according to arrangements that may be made with the City. 
c.	Where any user procures all or part of his water supply from sources other than the City, the user shall install and maintain at his own expense a flow measuring device of a type approved by the City. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(2)">	The character and concentration of the constituents of the waste water used in determining surcharges shall be determined by samples collected and analyzed by the City and/or industrial user. Samples shall be collected in such a manner as to be representative of the actual discharge and shall be analyzed using procedures set forth in ยง8-2137 of this article. 
</section>
   <section prefix="(3)">	The determination of the character and concentration of the constituents of the waste water discharge by the POTW Director or his duly appointed representatives shall be binding as a basis for charges. 
(Ord. No. 2011-981, ยง1, 12-6-11) 
</section>
  </section>
 </text>
</law>
