<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="Division" identifier="II" order_by="2" level="1">Division II - Planning and Development</unit>
  <unit label="part" identifier="11" order_by="11" level="2">PART 11 - TRANSPORTATION</unit>
  <unit label="chapter" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="3">CHAPTER 2. - MOTOR VEHICLES AND TRAFFIC</unit>
  <unit label="article" identifier="J" order_by="J" level="4">ARTICLE J. - PARKING AND STANDING</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="11-2177" order_by="11-2177" level="5">Sec. 11-2177. - STANDING FOR LOADING ONLY.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>11-2177</section_number>
 <catch_line>STANDING FOR LOADING ONLY.</catch_line>
 <order_by>11-2177</order_by>
 <text>
  <section prefix="(a)">	Passenger loading and unloading. 
No person shall stop, stand or park a vehicle for any purpose or period of time other than for the expeditious loading or unloading of passengers in any place marked as a passenger loading and unloading zone during the hours when the regulations applicable to such zones or stops are effective, and then for a period not to exceed ten (10) minutes. Passenger loading and unloading zones and the regulations applicable thereto, shall be as designated in official Traffic Schedule No. 16, &quot;Passenger Loading and Unloading Zones. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(b)">	Materials loading and unloading. 
No person shall stop, stand or park a vehicle for any purpose or length of time other than for the expeditious unloading and delivery, or pickup and loading of materials in any place marked as a loading and unloading zone during hours when the provisions applicable to loading zones are in effect. In no case shall the stop for loading or unloading of materials exceed sixty (60) minutes. Unless otherwise stated these loading zones shall be in effect from 9:00 a.m. to 5:00 p.m., Monday through Saturday. Materials loading and unloading zones and the regulations applicable thereto shall be as designated in official Traffic Schedule No. 17, &quot;Materials Loading and Unloading Zones.&quot; 
</section>
  <section prefix="(c)">	Exemption for television transmission. 
Notwithstanding provisions of this section to the contrary, and for the sole purpose of television signal transmission, it shall be lawful for a vehicle containing mobile television transmission equipment to park in a space designated as a passenger loading zone or a loading zone. Provided, however, that such vehicle shall only remain in the space for the minimum period of time required to prepare for the transmission of live television signals, and in no event for longer than one (1) hour. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(d)">	Truck loading zones. 
Truck loading zones shall be established as provided in this subsection. &quot;Truck loading&quot; shall mean the stopping or standing of any type of truck for the exclusive purpose of loading or unloading merchandise. For the purpose of definition in this section, a truck shall be classified as a vehicle designed to be used for the transportation of cargo including tractor trailer units, single-unit trucks, vans displaying a North Carolina commercial license plate (two (2) alphabetical characters followed by four (4) numeric characters), and pickup trucks; but excluding vehicles not principally designed for the transportation or cargo, such as motorcycles, passenger cars with or without trailers, station wagons or other noncargo vehicles. It shall be unlawful for trucks to park in official truck loading zones except for the exclusive purpose of loading or unloading merchandise. Truck loading zones and the regulations applicable thereto, shall be as designated in official Traffic Schedule No. 18, &quot;Truck Loading Zones.&quot; 
</section>
  <section prefix="(e)">	Commercial vehicle only loading zone. 
</section>
  <section prefix="(i)">	Definition. For purposes of this section, &quot;commercial vehicle&quot; shall mean a truck or other vehicle upon which the name, logo, or other designation of the person owning or operating the vehicle is painted or otherwise permanently affixed to the vehicle in letters or markings at least two inches in height, or which displays a valid North Carolina commercial license plate. 
(ii)	Use, generally. It shall be unlawful for any person to either (1) park any vehicle, other than a commercial vehicle, in any commercial loading zone as designated by the City in official Traffic Schedule No. 24, or (2) during the enforcement hours described in Traffic Schedule No. 24, &quot;Commercial Loading Zones,&quot; to utilize a commercial loading zone for any purpose other than expeditiously loading or unloading property, goods or merchandise from a commercial vehicle. In addition to any applicable fine or penalty, any vehicle parked in violation of this section shall be subject to being ticketed or cited at the discretion of any law enforcement officer or parking enforcement officer. 
(iii)	Area affected. This section shall apply only within the downtown business district bounded by East Street on the East, West Street and Glenwood Avenue on the West, Peace Street on the North and South Street to the South. Commercial loading zones and the regulations applicable thereto, shall be designated in official Traffic Schedule No. 24, &quot;Commercial Loading Zones.&quot; 
(Code 1959 , §21-28; Ord. No. 2006-990, §§1, 2, 3-21-06; Ord. No. 2006-67, §§1, 2, 8-8-06) 
Cross reference: Schedules incorporated by reference, §11-2004 
</section>
 </text>
</law>
