<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<law>
 <structure>
  <unit label="Division" identifier="II" order_by="2" level="1">Division II - Planning and Development</unit>
  <unit label="part" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="2">PART 8 - PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit>
  <unit label="chapter" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="3">CHAPTER 2. - WATER AND SEWER SERVICE</unit>
  <unit label="article" identifier="A" order_by="A" level="4">ARTICLE A. - GENERAL PROVISIONS</unit>
  <unit label="section" identifier="8-2011" order_by="8-2011" level="5">Sec. 8-2011. - PAYMENT OF FEES AND CHARGES.</unit>
 </structure>
 <section_number>8-2011</section_number>
 <catch_line>PAYMENT OF FEES AND CHARGES.</catch_line>
 <order_by>8-2011</order_by>
 <text>
Any person using the utility system shall pay all required permits, fees, and charges as required by laws, ordinances, and resolutions. 
Prior to a customer receiving potable water and/or sanitary sewer service from the City's utility system, an application for service must be received by the City's Utility Billing Office. For new customer accounts, this service application is received in the form of a utility connection permit. For existing utility system service accounts, customers must contact the Utility Billing Office to close or initiate service in the new customer's name. In order to initiate service on a new account or to initiate service on an existing account in the name of a new customer, an initiation fee must be billed to the customer and collected by the City in the customer's first utility bill mailed to the customer. Failure of the customer to pay the full amount of the initiation fee will be treated in the same manner as the utility bill being past due. 
A utility service initiation fee will be established by City Council and kept on record in the Schedule of Fees and Charges kept in the office of the Finance Director. This fee shall be billed by the City Utility Billing office as described in this section. The City's utility system customers are required to pay for their utility service by a date specified on their utility system bill. Failure to pay their bill by this date will result in the addition of a delinquency fee added to the amount past due on their utility bill. The delinquency fee and the past due utility bill amount must be paid in full to the City, in order for the customer's utility account to be considered current. Failure of the customer to pay the full amount of the delinquency fee will be treated in the same manner as the utility bill being past due for the customer's next utility bill and grounds for utility service interruption by the City, if not paid in full in the subsequent utility bill. 
(Ord. No. 1985-543, ยง11, 4-16-85; Ord. No. 2003-461, ยง1, 6-17-03; Ord. No. 2009-608, ยง6, 6-16-09, eff. 12-1-09) 
</text>
</law>
